the following is a conversation with
以下是与之对话
Stuart Russell he's a professor of
斯图尔特 罗素 他是教授
computer science at UC Berkeley and a
加州大学伯克利分校的计算机科学和
co-author of a book that introduced me
介绍我 的一本书的合着者
and millions of other people to the
和数百万其他人 给 的
amazing world of AI called artificial
人工智能的神奇世界叫做人工
intelligence a modern approach so it was
智能是一种现代方法， 所以它是
an honor for me to have this
我很荣幸能拥有这个
conversation as part of MIT course and
谈话麻省理工学院课程的一部分 ，
artificial general intelligence and the
人工智能 和 人工智能
artificial intelligence podcast if you
人工智能播客如果你
enjoy it please subscribe on youtube
享受它， 请 在 youtube上 订阅
itunes or your podcast provider of
itunes或你的播客提供商
choice or simply connect with me on
选择或只是与我联系
twitter at Lex Friedman spelled Fri D
Lex Friedman的 推文 拼写为Fri D.
and now here's my conversation with
现在这是我的对话
Stuart Russell so you've mentioned in
Stuart Russell所以你提到过
1975 in high school you've created one
1975年在高中你创造了一个
year first AI programs that play chess
第一年下棋的人工智能节目
were you ever able to build a program
你有没有能够建立一个程序
that beat you a chess or another board
国际象棋或其他棋盘
game so my program never beat me at
游戏，所以我的程序一直没有打我的
chess I actually wrote the program at
国际象棋我实际上写了这个程序
Imperial College so I used to take the
帝国理工学院， 所以我曾经采取过
bus every Wednesday with a box of cards
每周三有一盒公共汽车
this big and shove them into the card
这么大，把它们 塞进卡片里
reader and they gave us eight seconds of
读者，他们给了我们八秒钟
CPU time
CPU时间
it took about five seconds to read the
花了大约五秒钟来阅读
cards in and compile the code so we had
卡片并编译代码，所以我们有
three seconds of CPU time which was
三秒钟的CPU时间
enough to make one move you know with a
足以让你知道一个动作
not very deep search and then we would
搜索不是很深，然后我们会
print that move out and then we'd have
打印出去然后我们就有了
to go to the back of the queue and wait
去队列 的后面 等待
to feed the cards in again how do you
再次喂卡你怎么样
post a search well I would talk to no I
发布搜索好，我会跟 我没有
think we got we got an eight move eight
认为我们得到了我们得到了 一个 八个举动8
you know depth eight with alpha beta and
你知道深度八与alpha beta和
we had some tricks of our own about move
我们有一些关于移动的技巧
ordering and some pruning of the tree
订购和树的修剪
and we were still able to beat that
我们仍然能够击败它
program yeah yeah I I was a reasonable
程序是的是的我， 我是一个合理的
chess player in my youth I did Anna
我年轻的国际象棋选手我做了安娜
fellow program and a backgammon program
同伴节目和步步高节目
so when I go to Berkley I worked a lot
所以当我去 伯克利时，我工作了很多
on what we call meta reasoning which
在我们所谓的元推理中
really means reasoning about reasoning
真的意味着推理的推理
and in the case of a game playing
在游戏的情况下
program you need to reason about what
程序你需要推理什么
parts of the search tree you're actually
你实际上是搜索树的一部分
going to explore because the search tree
要探索因为搜索树
is enormous or you know bigger than the
巨大或者你知道的比越大
number of atoms in the universe and the
宇宙中 的原子数 和
way programs succeed and the way humans
计划成功的方式和人类的方式
succeed is by only looking at a small
成功只是看一个小的
fraction of the search tree and if you
搜索树的一部分，如果你
look at the right fraction you play
看看你演奏的正确分数
really well if you look at the wrong
如果 你 看错了，真的很好
fraction if you waste your time thinking
分数， 如果你浪费 你的 时间 思考
about things that are never gonna happen
关于永远 不会发生的事情
the moves that no one's ever gonna make
没有人会做出的举动
then you're gonna lose because you you
然后你会因为你而失败
won't be able to figure out the right
将无法找出 正确 的
decision
决定
so that question of how machines can
那么机器 如何 可以的问题
manage their own computation either how
管理自己的计算无论 怎样
they decide what to think about
他们决定 要 考虑 什么
is the meta-reasoning question we
是我们的元推理问题
developed some methods for doing that
开发了一些方法来做到 这一点
and very simply a machine should think
并且非常简单的 机器应该思考
about whatever thoughts are going to
关于什么想法要
improve its decision quality we were
提高 我们的 决策 质量
able to show that both for a fellow
能够证明 这两个人都是一个人
which is a standard to play game and for
这是玩游戏的标准
backgammon which includes dice for also
步步高包括骰子 还
it's a two-player game with uncertainty
这是一场有着不确定性的双人游戏
for both of those cases we could come up
对于这两方面的情况下，我们可以拿出
with algorithms that were actually much
算法实际上很多
more efficient than the standard alpha
比 标准 alpha更有效
beta search which chess programs at the
beta搜索哪些国际象棋程序
time we're using and that those programs
我们正在使用的时间和那些程序
could beat me and I think you can see
可以打败我，我想你可以看到
same basic ideas in alphago and alpha
alphago和 alpha中相同的基本思想
zero today the way they explored the
今天零他们探索的方式
tree is using a former meta reasoning to
树正在使用 前元 推理
select what to think about based on how
根据具体情况选择要考虑的内容
useful it is to think about it is there
有用的是考虑 它的存在
any insights you can describe without
你可以描述的任何见解
Greek symbols of how do we select which
希腊符号我们如何选择哪个
paths to go down there's really two
那里的路径真的有两条路
kinds of learning going on so as you say
正如你所说，正在进行各种学习
alphago learns to evaluate board
alphago学会评估董事会
position so it can it can look at a go
位置所以它可以看到一个去
board and it actually has probably a
董事会，它实际上可能有一个
superhuman ability to instantly tell how
超人能够即时告诉如何
promising that situation is to me the
承诺这种情况对我而言
amazing thing about alphago is not that
关于alphago的惊人之处 不是那个
it can be the world champion with its
它可以是世界冠军 ，其
hands tied behind his back but the fact
双手绑在他背后， 但事实
that if you stop it from searching
如果你停止搜索
altogether so you say okay you're not
完全如此你说好吧你 不是
allowed to do any thinking ahead
允许 做任何 超前 思维
right you can just consider each of your
对，你可以考虑 你的 每一个
legal moves and then look at the
合法的举动，然后看看
resulting situation and evaluate it so
由此产生的情况并对其进行评估
what we call a depth one search so just
我们所说 的 深度一个搜索所以才
the immediate outcome of your moves and
你的行动的直接结果
decide if that's good or bad
决定这是好还是 坏
that version of alphago can still play
那个版本的alphago仍然可以玩
at a professional level right and human
在专业水平上 权利和人性
professionals are sitting there for five
专业人士坐在那里五
ten minutes deciding what to do and
十分钟决定做什么和做什么
alphago in less than a second
alphago 不到一秒钟
instantly into it what is the right move
什么才是正确的举动
to make based on its ability to evaluate
根据其 评估 能力来制作
positions and that is remarkable because
位置， 这是值得注意的，因为
you know we don't have that level of
你知道我们没有 这个水平
intuition about go we actually have to
关于 我们实际上必须去的 直觉
think about the situation so anyway that
想想 这样 的情况 反正
capability that alphago has is one big
alphago的 能力 是一个大的
part of why it beats humans the other
为什么它击败人类的另一部分
big part is that it's able to look ahead
很重要的是它能够向前看
40 50 60 moves into the future mm-hmm
40 50 60进入未来mm-hmm
and you know if it was considering all
你知道它是否在考虑所有问题
possibilities 40 or 50 or 60 moves into
可能性40或50或60进入
the future that would be you know 10 to
未来，你会知道10到
possibility so wait way more than you
可能性等等比你更等待
know atoms in the universe and and so on
知道宇宙中的 原子 等等
so it's very very selective about what
所以它对什么是非常有选择性的
it looks at
它 着眼于
so let me try to give you an intuition
所以让我试着 给你一个 直觉
about how you decide what to think about
关于你如何决定 考虑什么
it's a combination of two things one is
它是两 件事 的组合
how promising it is right so if you're
如果你是的话，这是多么有希望
already convinced that a move is
已经确信此举是有道理的
terrible there's no point spending a lot
可怕的是，没有必要花很多钱
more time convincing yourself that it's
更多的时间说服自己 这是
terrible because it's probably not gonna
可怕的，因为它 可能 不是 要去
change your mind so the the real reason
改变你的 想法，所以真正的 原因
you think is because there's some
你认为是因为有一些
possibility of changing your mind about
改变 主意的可能性
what to do mm-hmm
该怎么办mm-hmm
right and is that changing your mind
是的，这是改变 你的想法
that would result then in a better final
这将导致更好的决赛
action in the real world so that's the
在现实世界中的行动，所以这是
purpose of thinking is to improve the
思考的目的是改善
final action in the real world and so if
在现实世界中的 最终 行动 ， 如果
you think about a move that is
你想一想 这 是 一个举动
guaranteed to be terrible you can
你可以保证很糟糕
convince yourself is terrible and you're
说服自己是 可怕的，你是
still not gonna change your mind all
仍然不会 改变你的 想法 全部
right
对
but on the other hand you I suppose you
但另一方面 ，你我想你
had a choice between two moves one of
有两个动作 之一 之间的选择
them you've already figured out is
他们已经想到的是
guaranteed to be a draw let's say and
保证是 一个平局 让我们说和
then the other one looks a little bit
然后另一个看起来有点
worse like it looks fairly likely that
更糟糕的是它看起来很可能
if you make that move you're gonna lose
如果你采取行动，你将会失败
but there's still some uncertainty about
但是仍有一些 不确定性
the value of that move there's still
这一举动 的价值 仍有
some possibility that it will turn out
它 会变成 一种可能性
to be a win all right then it's worth
如果它是 一个胜利，那么它是值得的
thinking about that so even though it's
考虑到这一点，即使它是
less promising on average than the other
平均不太有希望
move which is guaranteed to be a draw
保证 是平局的 举动
there's still some purpose in thinking
思考还有一些目的
about it because there's a chance that
关于它， 因为有机会
you will change your mind and discover
你会改变 主意并发现
that in fact it's a better move so it's
事实上，这是一个更好的举动， 所以它是
a combination of how good the move
移动有多好
appears to be and how much I'm certainty
似乎又是多少，我肯定
there is about its value the more
关于它的价值越多
uncertainty the more it's worth thinking
不确定性越多值得思考
about because there's a higher upside if
因为 如果 有更高的 上升空间
you want to think of it that way and of
你想要这样想的
course in the beginning especially in
特别是在开始的时候
the alphago 0 formulation it's
在alphago 0配方 是
everything is shrouded in uncertainty so
一切都笼罩 在 不确定的情况下
you're really swimming in a sea of
你真的游泳的海洋
uncertainty so it benefits you too I
不确定性所以它有利于你嫌 我
mean actually following the same process
意思是实际遵循相同的过程
as you described but because you're so
正如你 所描述的那样 但是因为你是这样的
uncertain about everything you you
不确定你的一切
basically have to try a lot of different
基本上要尝试很多 不同的
directions yeah so so the early parts of
方向是的所以 早期的部分
the search tree a fairly bushy
搜索树 相当浓密
that it will when looking a lot of
它看起来很多
different possibilities but fairly
不同的 可能性 但公平
quickly the degree of certainty about
迅速 确定的程度
some of the moves I mean if a movies are
我的意思是电影是什么意思
really terrible you'll pretty quickly
你很快就会非常 可怕
find out right you lose half your pieces
找出正确的你失去了一半你的作品
or half your territory and and then
或者你的领土的一半然后
you'll say okay this this is not worth
你会说这没关系，这 是不值得
thinking about any more and then so a
再思考，然后再这样做了
further down the tree becomes very long
树下面变得很长
and narrow and you're following various
狭窄，你正在追随 各种各样的
lines of play you know 10 20 30 40 50
你知道的游戏线路10 20 30 40 50
moves into the future and you know
走向未来，你 知道
that's again it's something that human
那又是人类的东西
beings have a very hard time doing
众生很难做
mainly because they just lacked the
主要是因为他们只是 缺乏
short-term memory you just can't
你不能 短暂的记忆
remember a sequence of moves that's 50
记得举动的序列是50
movies long and you can't you can't
电影很长 ，你不能不能
imagine the board correctly for that
想象一下那个板子
money moves into the future of course
钱当然会进入未来
the top players I'm much more familiar
我 更熟悉 的顶级球员
with chess but the top players probably
国际象棋，但可能是顶级球员
have they have echoes of the same kind
他们有 同类的 回声吗？
of intuition instinct that in a moment's
在一瞬间的直觉本能
time
时间
alphago applies when they see a board
alphago 在看到董事会时适用
I mean they've seen those patterns human
我的意思是他们已经看到了那些人类的模式
beings have seen those patterns before
众生以前见过这些模式
at the top at the Grandmaster level it
在位于广安门顶级 它
seems that there is some similarities or
似乎有一些相似之处 或
maybe it's it's our imagination creates
也许这就是我们的想象力所创造的
a vision of those similarities but it
这些 相似之处的愿景， 但它
feels like this kind of pattern
感觉就像这种模式
recognition that the alphago approaches
承认alphago接近
are using is similar to what human
正在使用的类似于人类
beings at the top level or using I think
最顶层的人或我认为的使用
there's there's some truth to that but
那里有一些事实， 但是
not entirely yeah I mean I think the the
不完全 是的我的意思是我认为的
extent to which a human Grandmaster can
程度人类棋手可以
reliably wreak instantly recognize the
可靠地发现了即时识别
right move instantly recognize the value
右移即刻识别价值
of a position I think that's a little
我认为这是一个立场
bit overrated but if you sacrifice a
有点高估， 但 如果你牺牲了
queen for exam I mean there's these
女王考试我的意思是这些
there's these beautiful games of chess
有这些美丽的国际象棋游戏
with Bobby Fischer somebody where it's
与Bobby Fischer有人在哪里
seeming to make a bad move and I'm not
似乎做出了不好的举动，我不是
sure there's a
确定有一个
a perfect degree of calculation involved
涉及到完美的计算程度
were they've calculated all the possible
他们已经计算了所有 可能的
things that happen but there's an
发生的事情， 但有一个
instinct there right that somehow adds
本能就是以某种方式增加
up to the yeah so I think what happens
到了是的 所以 我想 会发生什么
is you you you get a sense that there's
是你， 你有一种感觉，那就是
some possibility in the position even if
即使这个位置也有可能
you make a weird-looking move that it
你做了一个奇怪的举动
opens up some some lines of of
开辟了一些线索
calculation that otherwise would be
否则将是计算
definitely bad and and is that intuition
绝对是坏事，而且是直觉
that there's something here in this
这里有一些东西
position that might might yield a win
职位 可能会产生一个双赢
down the side and then you follow that
在 旁边 然后你跟着 它
right and and in some sense when when a
正确而且在某种意义上何时何时
chess player is following a line and in
国际象棋选手跟随一条线并进入
his or her mind they're they mentally
他或她的思想是 他们在精神上
simulating what the other person is
模拟对方是什么
gonna do while the opponent is gonna do
在对手要做的时候会做的
and they can do that as long as the
他们能做到这一点， 只要
moves are kind of forced right as long
举动是一种被迫的权利
as there's a you know there's a fourth
因为 你知道有第四个
we call a forcing variation where the
我们称之为强制变异
opponent doesn't really have much choice
对手并没有太多 选择
how to respond and then you see if you
如何回应，然后你看你是否
can force them into a situation where
可以迫使他们进入一种情况
you win you know we see plenty of
你赢了，你知道，我们看到很多 的
mistakes even even in Grandmaster games
甚至在 Grandmaster游戏中 也会出错
where they just miss some simple three
他们只是错过了一些简单的 三个
four five move combination that you know
你知道的 四五 组合组合
wasn't particularly apparent in in the
在...中并不是特别明显
position but we're still there that's
位置，但我们仍然有多数民众赞成
the thing that makes us human
让我们成为 人类的东西
yeah so when you mentioned that in a
是的， 所以当你提到那个
fellow those games were after some meta
这些游戏的同事是在一些元之后
reasoning improvements and research I
推理改进和研究我
was able to beat you how did that make
能够击败你这是怎么做的
you feel part of the meta reasoning
你觉得元推理的一部分
capability that it had was based on
它所具备的能力
learning and and you could sit down the
学习，你可以坐下 来
next day and you could just feel that it
第二天，你可以 感受到它
had got a lot smarter boom you know and
你知道并且有更多 更智能的 热潮
all the sudden you really felt like you
突然间你真的觉得像你一样
sort of pressed against
有点紧迫
the wall because it was it was much more
墙，因为它是更多
aggressive and was totally unforgiving
好斗并且完全无情
of any minor mistake that you might make
任何小的失误，你可能使
and and actually it seemed understood
实际上它似乎被理解了
the game better than I did and you know
这场比赛比我做得更好，你知道
Gary Kasparov has this quote weary
加里卡斯帕罗夫 这句话 疲惫不堪
during his match against deep blue he
在 他与 深蓝色的 比赛中 他
said he suddenly felt that there was a
说他突然觉得有一个
new kind of intelligence across the
全新的智慧
board do you think that's a scary or an
董事会你认为这是一个可怕的或一个
exciting possibility that's prevent for
激动人心的可能性
yourself in in the context of chess
你自己在国际象棋的背景下
purely sort of in this like that feeling
纯粹 就像那种 感觉一样
whatever that is I think it's definitely
无论那是什么，我认为这绝对是
an exciting feeling you know this is
一种令人兴奋的 感觉， 你知道这是
what made me work on AI in the first
是什么让我在第一个工作AI
place was as soon as I really understood
我真的明白了
what a computer was I wanted to make it
我想做什么计算机
smart you know I started out with the
聪明，你知道我开始 了
first program I wrote was for the
我写的第一个程序是为了
sinclair programmable calculator and i
辛克莱可编程计算器 和 我
think you could write a 21 step
认为你可以写一个21步
algorithm that was the biggest program
算法是最大的程序
you could write something like that and
你可以写 类似的 东西 和
do little arithmetic calculations so I
做一点算术计算所以我
say think I implemented Newton's method
说我认为我实施了牛顿的方法
for square roots and a few other things
对于平方根和其他一些事情
like that
这样 的
um but then you know I thought okay if I
嗯但是你知道我认为如果我
just had more space I could make this
我有更多的空间 可以做到这一点
thing intelligent
事情聪明
and so I started thinking about AI and
所以我开始考虑AI和
and I think the the the thing that's
而且我认为那 是事情
scary is not is not the chess program
可怕的不是 国际象棋程序
because you know chess programs they're
因为你知道 他们的 国际象棋程序
not in they're taking over the world
不是他们正在接管世界
business but if you extrapolate
商业， 但如果你推断
you know there are things about chess
你知道有关国际象棋的事情
that don't resemble the real world right
这并不像现实世界 中 的权利
we know we know the rules of chess
我们知道我们知道 国际象棋的规则
chess board is completely visible to the
国际象棋棋盘完全可见
programmer of course the real world is
程序员当然是现实世界
not most you most the real world is not
不是你最多的现实世界不是
visible from wherever you're sitting so
从你坐的任何地方都可以看到
to speak
说话
and to overcome those kinds of problems
并克服这些问题
you need qualitatively different
你需要质的不同
algorithms another thing about the real
算法关于真实的算法
world is that you know we we regularly
世界是 你知道我们经常我们
plan ahead on the timescales involving
提前计划涉及的时间表
billions or trillions of steps now we
现在我们有数十亿甚至数万亿的步骤
don't plan that was in detail but you
不要计划那个细节 但是你
know when you choose to do a PhD at
知道，当你选择在 做博士
Berkeley
伯克利
that's a five-year commitment and that
这是一个为期五年的承诺 ，
amounts to about a trillion motor
达约 一万亿马达
control steps that you will eventually
控制你最终会采取的步骤
be committed to including going up the
致力于 包括上升
stairs opening doors drinking water type
楼梯打开门 饮用水类型
yeah I mean every every finger movement
是的我的意思是每一个手指运动
while you're typing every character of
当你输入的每个角色时
every paper and the thesis and
每篇论文和论文 和
everything else so you're not commuting
其他一切， 所以你 不通勤
in advance to the specific motor control
提前进行特定的电机控制
steps but you're still reasoning on a
步骤， 但你仍然在推理
timescale that will eventually reduce to
时间尺度 最终将减少到
trillions of motor control actions and
数万亿的电机控制动作和
so for all these reasons
因为所有这些原因
you know alphago and and deep blue and
你知道alphago和深蓝色 和
so on don't represent any kind of threat
所以 不代表任何形式的威胁
to humanity but they are a step towards
对人类而言，他们迈出了一步
it right near that and progress in AI
它就在那附近并且在AI中取得进展
occurs by essentially removing one by
通过基本上删除一个发生
one these assumptions that make problems
这些假设会产生问题
easy like the assumption of complete
容易就像完成的假设
observability of the situation right we
对我们 的情况的可观察性
remove that assumption you need a much
删除你需要的 假设
more complicated kind of a computing
更复杂 的计算方式
design and you need something that
设计，你需要的东西
actually keeps track of all the things
实际上跟踪 所有的事情
you can't see and tries to estimate
你无法看到并试图估计
what's going on and there's inevitable
发生了什么，这是不可避免的
uncertainty in that so it becomes a much
在 这种不确定性，使其成为一个更
more complicated problem but you know we
更复杂的问题，但你知道我们
are removing those assumptions we are
正在消除我们的假设
starting to have algorithms that can
开始有可以的算法
cope with much longer timescales
应对更长的时间尺度
they can cope with uncertainty they can
他们可以应对不确定因素
cope with partial observability
应对部分可观察性
and so each of those steps sort of
所以每个步骤都是如此
magnifies by a thousand the range of
放大千倍的范围
things that we can do with AI systems so
我们可以用AI系统做的事情
the way I started me I wanted to be a
我启动我的方式我想成为一个
psychiatrist for long time to understand
精神科医生很长 一段时间来了解
the mind in high school and of course
高中时的思想，当然还有
program and so on and then I showed up
程序等等 然后我出现了
University of Illinois to an AI lab and
伊利诺伊 大学 的AI实验室和
they said okay I don't have time for you
他们说没关系，我没 时间给你
but here's a book AI a modern approach I
但这里有一本书AI现代的方法， 我
think was the first edition at the time
认为是当时 的 第一版
mmm here go go learn this and I remember
嗯这里去 学习这个，我记得
the lay of the land was well it's
这片土地很好
incredible that we solve chess but we'll
令人难以置信的是我们 解决了国际象棋但我们会
never solve go I mean it was pretty
从来没有解决过我的意思是它很漂亮
certain that go in the way we thought
肯定会影响我们的想法
about systems that reason was impossible
关于理性不可能的系统
to solve and now we've solved this as a
要解决，现在我们已经解决了 这个 问题
very I think I would have said that it's
我想我会说 是的
unlikely we could take the kind of
我们不太可能采取那种方式
algorithm that was used for chess and
这是用于 国际象棋的算法和
just get it to scale up and work well
刚刚得到它的规模 ， 并运行良好
for go
去吧
and at the time what we thought was that
当时我们的想法是那样的
in order to solve go we would have to do
为了 解决 我们必须要做的事情
something similar to the way humans
类似于 人类的方式
manage the complexity of go which is to
管理go的复杂性
break it down into kind of sub games so
把它分解成 一种子游戏
when a human thinks about a go board
当一个人想到一个去板
they think about different parts of the
他们考虑的是不同的部分
board as sort of weakly connected to
董事会就像弱者一样
each other and they think about okay
对方以及他们 对 好吗
within this part of the board here's how
在这部分董事会中，这是如何做到的
things could go and that part about his
事情可以去，那部分关于他的
how things could go and now you try to
事情怎么会去，现在你尝试
sort of couple those two analyses
那两种分析结合起来
together and deal with the interactions
一起处理互动
and maybe revise your views of how
也许修改你对如何的看法
things are going to go in each part and
事情将在每个部分进行
then you've got maybe five six seven ten
那么你有可能五六百七点十分
parts of the board and that actually
董事会的一部分，实际上
resembles the real world much more than
比现实世界更像
chess does because in the real world you
国际象棋确实是因为在现实世界中你
know we have work we have home life we
知道我们有工作我们有家庭生活 我们
have sport you know whatever different
有运动你知道什么不同
kinds of activities you know shopping
你知道 购物的各种活动
these all are connected to each other
所有这些都互相连接
but they're weakly connected so when I'm
但是，当我这么做的时候， 它们之间的联系很弱
typing a paper you know I don't simul
打字纸 你知道我不会 同意
taneous Li have to decide which order
李李必须决定哪个订单
I'm gonna get the you know the milk and
我会让你知道牛奶和牛奶
the butter you know that doesn't affect
你知道的黄油不会影响
the typing but I do need to realize okay
打字，但我确实需要实现
better finish this before the shops
在 商店 之前更好地完成这个
closed because I don't have anything you
关闭，因为 我什么都没有
don't have any food at home all right
没有任何食物在家里 没事
right so there's some weak connection
对，所以有一些弱连接
but not in the way that chess works
但不是国际象棋的方式
where everything is tied into a single
所有东西都捆绑在一起
stream of thought so the thought was
思想流，因此 想到的是
that go just sort of go we'd have to
我们必须这样做
make progress on stuff that would be
在那些 可能的东西上取得进展
useful for the real world and in a way
对现实 世界和某种方式 有用
alphago is a little bit disappointing
alphago 有点令人失望
right because the the program designed
对， 因为该程序设计
for alphago was actually not that
对于alphago实际上并非 如此
different from from deep blue or even
不同于深蓝色甚至是深蓝色
from Arthur Samuels checker playing
来自Arthur Samuels的 格子游戏
program from the 1950s
从 20世纪50年代的计划
and in fact the so the two things that
而事实上这样的两件事情 ，
make alphago work is one one is is
让alphago工作就是一个人
amazing ability ability to evaluate the
评估 能力惊人 能力
positions and the other is the
位置和 另一种是
meta-reasoning capability which which
元推理能力
allows it to to explore some paths in
允许它探索一些路径
the tree very deeply and to abandon
树深深地放弃了
other paths very quickly so this word
其他路径 很快就 这么说了
meta-reasoning while technically correct
在技​​术上正确的元推理
inspires perhaps the the wrong degree of
激励也许是错误的程度
power that alphago has for example the
例如 ，alphago 具有的力量
word reasonings as a powerful word let
单词推理作为一个有力的词令
me ask you sort of so you were part of
我问你，所以你参与其中
the symbolic AI world for a while like
象征AI世界就像一个同时
whatever the AI was there's a lot of
无论AI是什么，都有很多
excellent interesting ideas there that
那里有很棒的有趣想法
unfortunately met a winter and so it do
不幸遇到了一个冬天，所以它
you think it really emerges well I would
你认为它真的很好
say yeah it's not quite as simple as
说是的，它不是那么简单
that so the the AI winter so for the
所以AI冬天如此
first window that was actually named as
这 实际上称之为 第一窗口
such was the one in the late 80s
这是80年代后期的那个
and that came about because in the mid
并且， 在中期出现， 因为
80s there was a really a concerted
80年代有一个真正的协调
attempt to push AI out into the real
试图将 AI推向现实
world using what was called expert
世界使用所谓的 专家
system technology and for the most part
系统技术和大部分
that technology was just not ready for
那项技术还没准备好
primetime
黄金时间
they were trying in many cases to do a
他们在很多情况下都试图去做
form of uncertain reasoning judge you
不确定推理的形式判断你
know judgment combinations of evidence
知道判断组合的证据
diagnosis those kinds of things which
诊断那些东西
was simply invalid and when you try to
只是无效 ， 当你尝试
apply invalid reasoning methods to real
将无效推理方法应用于实际
problems you can fudge it for small
你可以把它捏成小问题
versions of the problem but when it
问题的版本， 但当它
starts to get larger the thing just
事情开始变大
falls apart so many companies found that
分崩离析 ，许多公司发现了这一点
the stuff just didn't work and they were
这些东西不起作用，他们是
spending tons of money on consultants to
把大量的 钱花在顾问身上
try to make it work and
试着让它发挥作用
there were you know other practical
你 知道其他的实用 吗？
reasons like you know they they were
像你这样的原因， 他们知道他们 是
asking the companies to buy incredibly
要求公司购买令人难以置信
expensive lisp machine workstations
昂贵的lisp机器工作站
which were literally between fifty and a
这实际上是在五十和一个之间
hundred thousand dollars in you know in
你知道几十万美元
1980s money which was would be like
20世纪80年代的钱就是这样的
between a hundred and fifty and three
一百五十三
hundred thousand dollars per workstation
每个 工作站 十万美元
in current prices so then the bottom
在目前的价格， 所以然后底部
line they weren't seeing a profit from
他们没有从中获利
it yeah
是的
they in many cases I think there were
他们在很多情况下我认为 有
some successes there's no doubt about
一些成功毫无疑问
that but people I would say over
那个我会 说的 人
invested every major company was
投资了每家大公司
starting an AI department just like now
就像现在一样开始AI 部门
and I worry a bit that we might see
我担心我们会看到一点
similar disappointments not because the
类似的失望不是因为
technology is invalid but it's limited
技术无效，但有限
in its scope and it's almost the the
在它的范围内 它几乎是
dual of the you know the scope problems
双重你知道范围问题
that expert systems had so what have you
那些专家系统对你有什么帮助
learned from that hype cycle and what
从炒作周期中学到了什么
can we do to prevent another winter for
我们可以做些什么来阻止另一个冬天
example yeah so when I'm giving talks
例子是的，所以我在谈话的时候
these days that's one of the warnings
这些天是警告之一
that I give to to pot warning slide one
我给锅警告张幻灯片
is that you know rather than data being
是你知道而不是数据
the new oil data is the new snake oil
新的石油数据是新的蛇油
that's a good line and then and then the
这是一个很好的线，然后然后
other is that we might see a kind of
另一种是， 我们可能会看到一种
very visible failure in some of the
一些人中非常明显的失败
major application areas and I think
我认为主要的应用领域
self-driving cars would be the flagship
自动驾驶汽车将成为旗舰
and I think when you look at the history
当你看 历史时我想
so the first self-driving car was on the
所以第一辆自动驾驶汽车就在
freeway driving itself changing lanes
高速公路驾驶自己改变车道
overtaking in 1987 and so it's more than
1987年超车， 因此超过了
30 years and that kind of looks like
30 年 ，那种看起来 像
where we are today right you know
我们今天在哪里， 你知道
prototypes on the freeway changing lanes
高速公路改变车道上的原型
and overtaking now I think significant
现在我认为很重要
progress has been made particularly on
特别是取得了进展
the perception side so we worked a lot
感知方面，所以我们工作了很多
on autonomous vehicles in the early mid
在早期中期的自动驾驶汽车
90s at Berkley you know and we had our
伯克利 90年代， 你知道，我们有我们的
own big demonstrations you know we we
自己的大型示威你知道我们
put congressmen into yourself driving
让国会议员自己开车
cars and and had them zooming along the
汽车，并让他们沿着放大
freeway
高速公路
and the problem was clearly perception
问题显然是感知
at the time the problem that perception
当时认知的问题
yeah so in simulation with perfect
是的，在完美的模拟中
perception you could actually show that
感觉你实际上可以证明
you can drive safely for a long time
你可以安全驾驶很长一段时间
even if the other cars are misbehaving
即使 其他车辆行为不端
and and so on but simultaneously we
等等我们同时
worked on machine vision for detecting
致力于机器视觉检测
cars and tracking pedestrians and so on
汽车和跟踪行人等
and we couldn't get the reliability of
我们无法获得可靠性
detection and tracking up to a high
检测 和跟踪高达
enough particular level particularly in
特别 是在 特定的水平
bad weather conditions nighttime
恶劣的天气条件 夜间
rainfall good enough for demos but
降雨量足以进行演示但是
perhaps not good enough to cover the
也许不足以覆盖
general the general yeah the thing about
将军一般是的事情
driving is you know suppose you're a
开车是你知道的， 假设你是一个
taxi driver you know and you drive every
出租车司机， 你知道，你开车每一个
day eight hours a day for ten years
每天八小时， 十年
right that's a hundred million seconds
正确的 ，这是一个亿秒
of driving you know and any one of those
驾驶你知道那些 中的 任何一个
seconds you can make a fatal mistake so
几秒钟，你可以 犯 这样 一个致命的 错误
you're talking about eight nines of
你说的是八个九
reliability right now if your vision
如果你的愿景，现在可靠性
system only detects ninety eight point
系统只检测到 九十八点
three percent of the vehicles right and
3％的车辆正确和
that's sort of you know one on a bit
你有点熟悉这一点
nines and reliability so you have
九，可靠性， 所以你有
another seven orders of magnitude to go
再去七个数量级
and and this is what people don't
这是人们没有的
understand they think oh because I had a
明白他们认为哦 因为我有一个
successful demo I'm pretty much done but
成功的演示我已经完成了很多但是
you know you're not even within seven
你知道你甚至不在七岁以内
orders of magnitude of being done and
完成的数量级 和
that's the difficulty and it's it's not
这就是困难，而事实并非如此
there can I follow a white line that's
我可以按照白线进行操作
not the problem right we follow a white
没有问题的正确的 ，我们遵循一个白色
line all the way across the country
一路 走遍全国各地
but it's the it's the weird stuff that
但这就是奇怪的东西
happens it's some of the edge cases yeah
发生它是一些边缘案件是啊
the edge case other drivers doing weird
边缘案例其他司机做得很奇怪
things you know so if you talk to Google
你知道的事情，如果你 与谷歌交谈
right so they had actually very
对，所以他们实际上非常
classical architecture where you know
你知道的古典建筑
you had machine vision which would
你有机器视觉这将
detect all the other cars and
检测所有其他汽车和
pedestrians and the white lines and the
行人和白线和
road signs and then basically that was
道路标志，然后基本上 是那样的
fed into a logical database and then you
输入逻辑 数据库，然后你
had a classical 1970s rule-based expert
有一个20世纪70年代的经典规则专家
system telling you okay if you're in the
系统告诉你， 如果你在
middle lane and there's a bicyclist in
中间车道，里面有骑自行车的人
the right lane who is signaling this
右边车道谁是这个信号
then then then don't need to do that
然后然后不需要这样做
yeah right and what they found was that
是的，他们发现的 是那个
every day they go out and there'd be
他们每天出去都会有
another situation that the rules didn't
规则没有的 另一种情况
cover you know so they they come to a
盖住你知道所以他们来到了
traffic circle and there's a little girl
交通圈，还有一个小 女孩
riding a bicycle the wrong way around a
骑自行车的方式错 了
traffic circle okay what do you do we
交通圈 好吗，你 做什么我们
don't have a rule oh my god okay stop
没有规则 哦，我的上帝好吧停下来
and then you know they come back and had
然后你知道他们回来了
more rules and they just found that this
更多的规则，他们只是发现了这一点
was not really converging
并没有真正融合
and and if you think about it right how
并且，如果你正确地考虑如何
how do you deal with an unexpected
你怎么处理意外的事情
situation meaning one that you've never
情况意味着你永远不会
previously encountered and the sort of
以前遇到和排序
the the reasoning required to figure out
要弄清楚的理由
the solution for that situation has
这种 情况的解决方案 有
never been done it doesn't match any
从来没有做过它不匹配任何
previous situation in terms of the kind
以前的情况就种类而言
of reasoning you have to do well you
推理你必须做得好
know in chess programs this happens all
在国际象棋程序中知道 这一切都发生
the time
时间
you're constantly coming up with
你不断想出
situations you haven't seen before and
你以前没有见过的情况和
you have to reason about them you have
你必须 推理他们
to think about okay here are the
考虑好在这里是
possible things I could do here the
可能的 事情，我可以在这里做的
outcomes here's how desirable the
结果在这里是多么可取的
outcomes are and then pick the right one
结果然后选择正确的结果
you know in the 90s we were saying okay
你知道在90年代我们说没关系
this is how you're gonna have to do
这就是你要做的事情
automated vehicles they're gonna have to
自动驾驶车辆，他们将得
have a look ahead capability but the
有一个向前看能力， 但
look ahead for driving is more difficult
提前开车 比较困难
than it is for chess because Huysmans
绝对比 国际象棋，因为斯曼
the other right there's humans and
另一个是人类和
they're less predictable than just a
他们不像一个人那么可预测
standard well then will you have an
标准那么你 会有一个
opponent in chess who's also somewhat
国际象棋中的对手也有所作为
unpredictable but for example in chess
不可预测但例如 在国际象棋中
you always know the opponent's intention
你总是知道对手的意图
they're trying to beat you right whereas
他们试图打败你 的权利，而
in driving you don't know is this guy
在开车你不知道是这个家伙
trying to turn left or has he just
试图向左转或 他只是
forgotten to turn off his tone signal or
忘 了关掉他的音调 信号 或
is he drunk or is he you know changing
他喝醉了还是 你知道改变了
the channel on his radio or whatever it
收音机里的频道或其他频道
might be you got to try and figure out
可能是你 得试着 找出
the mental state the intent of the other
心理状态 是另一方的意图
drivers to forecast the possible
司机预测可能
evolutions of their trajectories and
他们的轨迹和演变的演变
then you've got to figure out okay which
然后你必须弄明白 哪个 好
is the directory for me that's going to
是我 要去的目录
be safest and those all interact with
最安全，那些都与之互动
each other because the other drivers
彼此 因为其他 司机
going to react to your trajectory and so
对 你的轨迹 做出反应 等等
on so you know they've got the classic
所以你 知道他们 有 经典之作
merging onto the freeway a problem where
合并到高速公路上的问题在哪里
you're kind of racing a vehicle that's
你有点像赛车一样
already on the freeway and you are you
已经在高速公路上， 你就是你
gonna pull ahead of them or you're gonna
要拉 他们前面或者你 会
let them go first and pull in behind and
让他们先走 ，拉在后面，
you get this sort of uncertainty about
你这种不确定性的 约
who's going first
谁先走了
so all those kinds of things
所有这些事情
mean that you need decision-making
意味着你需要决策
architecture that's very different from
与...截然不同的建筑
either a rule-based system or it seems
无论是 基于规则的系统还是看起来如此
to me a kind of an end-to-end neural
对我来说是一种端到端的神经
network system you know so just as
网络系统， 你知道，所以 就像
alphago is pretty good when it doesn't
如果没有， alphago 相当不错
do any look ahead but it's way way way
做任何事，但这是方式
way better when it does I think the same
我认为 同样的方式更好
is going to be true for driving you can
你可以驾驶， 这 将是真实的
have a driving system that's pretty good
有一个非常好的驾驶系统
when it doesn't do any look ahead but
当它没有任何展望但是
that's not good enough you know and
你知道的并不够好
we've already seen multiple deaths
我们已经看到多处死亡
caused by poorly designed machine
设计不良的机器造成的
learning algorithms that don't really
学习算法并不是真的
understand what they're doing yeah and
了解他们正在做什么耶和华
on several levels I think it's on the
在几个层面我认为它是在
perception side there's mistakes being
感知方存在错误
made by those algorithms were the
通过这些算法作出是的
perception is very shallow on the
知觉是在很浅
planning side to look ahead like you
计划方面像你一样展望未来
said and the thing that we come come up
说， 我们来的东西出现了
against that's really interesting when
针对真的很有趣，当
you try to deploy systems in the real
您尝试在真实中部署系统
world is you can't think of an
世界是你想不到的
artificial intelligence system as a
人工智能系统 作为
thing that responds to the world always
永远回应世界的事物
you have to realize that it's an agent
你必须认识到 ， 这是一个代理
that others will respond to as well so
其他人也会这样回应
in order to drive successfully you can't
为了成功驾驶你不能
just try to do obstacle avoidance you
只是试着避开你
can't pretend that you're invisible
不能假装你是隐形的
thank you right you're the invisible car
谢谢你，你是隐形车
right just look that way I mean but you
是的，只是看起来 我的意思，但 你
have to assert yet others have to be
必须断言其他人必须
scared of you just we're all there's
害怕你， 只是我们都 在那里
this tension there's this game so if we
这种紧张就是这个游戏，如果我们
studied a lot of work with pedestrians
我和行人一起研究了很多工作
if you approach pedestrians as purely an
如果你接近行人纯粹是一个
obstacle avoidance so you either doing
避障，所以你要么 做
look ahead isn't modeling the intent
展望未来 并未 对意图进行建模
that you're you they're not going to
你是他们，他们不会
they're going to take advantage of you
他们会利用 你
they're not going to respect you at all
他们不会尊重你的一切
there has to be a tension a fear some
必须有一种紧张的恐惧
amount of uncertainty that's how we have
我们如何拥有的不确定性
create we or at least just a kind of a
创造我们或至少只是一种
resoluteness right so you have you have
坚决， 所以你有你
to display a certain amount of
显示一定数量 的
resoluteness you can't you can't be too
坚决你不能你也不能
tentative
试验
and yeah so the right the the solutions
是的，解决方案的权利
then become pretty complicated right you
对你来说变得相当复杂
get into game theoretic yes analyses and
进入游戏理论是分析和
so we're you know Berkeley now we're
所以我们现在知道伯克利了
working a lot on this kind of
在这种方面做了很多工作
interaction between machines and humans
机器 与人类 之间的互动
and that's exciting yeah and so my
那是令人兴奋的 ，所以我的
colleague and could drag an actually you
同事，实际上可以拖你
know if you if you formulate the problem
知道你是否制定了 问题
game theoretically and you just let the
理论上游戏，你只需要让
system figure out the solution you know
系统找出你知道的解决方案
it does interesting unexpected things
它做了有趣的意外事情
like sometimes at a stop sign
喜欢有时在停车标志
if no one is going first right the car
如果没有人会先 右侧，车
will actually back up a little all right
实际上备份 一点 没事
and just to indicate to the other cars
并且只是 为了向 其他车辆 表明
that they should go and that's something
他们应该去， 那是什么
it invented entirely by itself that's
它完全是由它自己发明的
interesting you know we didn't say this
有趣的是你知道我们没有这么说
is the language of communication at stop
是停止时 的沟通语言
signs it figured it out that's really
这标志着它真的发现了
interesting
有趣
so let me one just step back for a
所以让我 一个 刚刚退后一步 一
second just this beautiful philosophical
仅仅是这个美丽的哲学
notion so Pamela I'm a quartic in 1979
这个概念所以帕梅拉我是 1979年的 一个四分之一
wrote AI began with the ancient wish to
AI开始写着古老的愿望
forge the gods so when you think about
当你想到的时候就这样伪造了众神
the history of our civilization do you
我们文明的历史对你而言
think that there is an inherent desire
认为有一种 内在的愿望
to create let's not say gods but to
创造让我们不要说神但是
create super intelligence is it inherent
创造超级智能是它固有的
to us is it in our genes that the
对我们来说， 就是我们的基因
natural arc of human civilization is to
人类文明的自然弧线是
create things that are of greater and
创造更大的东西
greater power and perhaps no echoes of
更大的权力， 也许没有 回音
ourselves so to create the gods as
我们自己如此创造 神灵
Pamela said
帕梅拉说
if the maybe I mean you know we're all
如果可能我的意思是你知道我们都是
we're all individuals
我们都是个人
certainly we see over and over again in
当然，我们一遍又一 遍地看到
history individuals who thought about
历史上 个人思考过的人
this possibility hopefully when I'm not
当我不是时，希望这种可能性
being too philosophical here but if you
在这里 过于哲学 ，但如果你
look at the arc of this you know where
看看你知道哪里的弧线
this is going and we'll talk about AI
这是，我们将谈论人工智能
safety we'll talk about greater and
安全我们会谈论更大和更好
greater intelligence do you see that
你看到了更大的智慧吗？
there in when you created the earth
在你创造地球的时候
Allah program and you felt this
真主计划，你感觉到这一点
excitement
激动
what was that excitement was it
那令人兴奋的是它
excitement of a tinkerer who created
创造了一个修补匠的兴奋
something cool like a clock or was there
像 时钟 一样酷的东西或者在那里
a magic or was it more like a child
一个魔术还是更像 是一个孩子
being born that yeah you know yeah so I
出生，是的，你知道是的，所以我
mean I certainly understand that
我当然明白 这一点
viewpoint and if you look at the light
观点，如果你看光
he'll report which was commit so in the
他会报告哪个是 这样的
70s there was a lot of controversy in
20世纪70年代出现了一个争议颇多
the UK about AI and you know whether it
关于人工智能的英国，你知道是否
was for real and how much the money
是为了真实和多少钱
money the government should invest and
政府应该投资的钱
there was a lot long story but the
有很长的故事，但是
government commissioned a report by
政府委托 报告
by light Hill who was a physicist and he
作为物理学家 和他 的光山
wrote a very damning report about AI
写了一篇关于AI的非常诅咒的报道
which I think was the point and he said
我认为这是重点， 他说
that that these are you know frustrated
那些你知道沮丧的
men who unable to have children would
无法生孩子的男人会
like to create and you know create life
喜欢创造，你知道创造生活
you know as a kind of replacement you
你知道作为 一种 替代你
know which I which I think is really
知道我认为哪个是真的
pretty unfair
很不公平
but there is I mean there there is a
但我的意思是那里有一个
kind of magic I would say you when you
当你的时候我会说你的那种魔力
you build something
你建立了什么
and what you're building in is really
而你正在建造的是真的
just you're building in some
只是 你在建造一些
understanding of the principles of
理解的原则
learning and decision-making and to see
学习和决策，看看
those principles actually then turn into
那些原则实际上就变成了
intelligent behavior in in specific
特定的智能行为
situations it's an incredible thing and
情况下， 它是一个令人难以置信的事情 ，
you know that is naturally going to make
你知道，自然会 令
you think okay where does this end and
你认为这 可以在哪里结束
so there's a there's magical optimistic
所以有一种神奇乐观的态度
views of word and whatever your view of
单词的观点和你的观点
optimism is whatever your view of utopia
乐观是你对乌托邦的看法
is it's probably different for everybody
这对每个人来说可能都不一样
yeah but you've often talked about
是的，但你经常谈论
concerns you have of how things might go
你对事情的 进展感到担忧
wrong so I've talked to max tegmark
错了所以我跟 max tegmark 谈过 了
there's a lot of interesting ways to
有很多 的有趣的方式
think about AI safety you're one of the
想想人工智能安全你是其中之一
seminal people thinking about this
开创性的人在想这个
problem among sort of being in the weeds
排序 中杂草是 中问题
of actually solving specific AI problems
实际上解决特定的AI问题
you also think about the big picture of
你也想到了 大局
where we're going so can you talk about
我们要去的地方 ，所以 你 可以 谈
several elements of it let's just talk
它的几个要素让我们谈谈
about maybe the control problem so this
关于控制问题可能就是 这样
idea of losing ability to control the
失去控制能力的想法
behavior and of a AI system so how do
行为和AI系统如何做
you see that how do you see that coming
你看到你怎么看待即将来临
about what do you think we can do to
关于你认为我们能做些什么
manage it well so it doesn't take a
管理得好，因此并不 需要
genius to realize that if you make
天才意识到，如果你做
something that's smarter than you you
比你聪明的东西
might have a problem you know in Turing
你可能在 图灵 遇到一个问题
Alan Turing you know wrote about the
阿兰图灵你知道写了关于
gave lectures about this you know 19
你知道 19讲这个
1951 painted a lecture on the radio and
1951 年在广播和电视上 画了一个 讲座
he basically says you know once the
他基本上说你知道了
machine thinking method stops you know
机器 思维方法阻止 你知道
very quickly they'll outstrip humanity
他们很快就会超越人类
and you know if we're lucky we might be
你知道，如果我们幸运的话，我们可能 会
able to I think he says if we may be
能 ，我认为，他说，如果我们可能
able to turn off the power at strategic
能够在战略上 关闭 权力
moments but even so a species would be
时刻，但即使如此物种也会如此
humbled yeah you can actually I think
谦卑是啊你 其实我能想到的
was wrong about that right here is you
这是错的 ，这 就是你
you know if it's a sufficiently
你知道它是否足够了
intelligent machine is not gonna let you
智能机不会让你
switch it off so it's actually in
把它关掉所以它实际上是在
competition with you so what do you
和 你竞争那么你呢？
think is meant just for a quick tangent
认为只是为了 快速切线
if we shut off this super intelligent
如果我们关闭这个超级智能
machine that our species will be humbled
机器，我们的物种将谦卑
I think he means that we would realize
我认为他 意味着我们会意识到
that we are inferior right that we we
我们是我们的劣等权利
only survive by the skin of our teeth
只能靠 牙齿 的 皮肤 存活
because we happen to get to the off
因为我们恰巧到了
switch just in time
及时切换
you know and if we hadn't then we would
你知道，如果我们没有，那么我们会
have lost control over the earth
失去了 对 地球的 控制
so do you are you more worried when you
所以你在担心的时候会更加担心吗？
think about this stuff about super
想想关于超级的这些东西
intelligent AI or are you more worried
智能人工智能 还是 你更担心
about super powerful AI that's not
关于超级强大的 AI，不是
aligned with our values so the paperclip
与我们的价值观一致， 所以回形针
scenario is kind of I think so the main
场景是我认为的主要方式
problem I'm working on is is the control
我正在研究的问题是控制
problem the the problem of machines
问题是机器 的 问题
pursuing objectives that are as you say
追求像你说的目标
not aligned with human objectives and
不符合人类目标和
and this has been it has been the way
这一直是它 一直 的方式
we've thought about I eyes since the
我们也想过 ，因为我的眼睛
beginning you you build a machine for
从你开始为你建造一 台机器
optimizing and then you put in some
优化，然后你放入一些
objective and it optimizes right and and
目标 ，它优化权利和和
you know we we can think of this as the
你知道我们可以把它想象 成这样 的
the King Midas problem right because if
迈德斯国王的问题是正确的， 因为如果
you know so King Midas put in this
你知道吗，迈达斯国王就这么说了
objective right everything I touch you
客观的， 我触动你的一切
turned to gold and the gods you know
转向黄金和你知道的众神
that's like the machine they said okay
这就像他们说的好机器
done you know you now have this power
你知道你现在拥有这种力量吗？
and of course his food and his drink and
当然还有他的食物，他的饮料 ，
his family all turned to gold and then
他的家人都变成了金子然后
he's sighs misery and starvation and
他感叹苦难和饥饿
this is you know it's it's a warning
这是你知道的， 这是一个警告
it's it's a failure mode that pretty
这是一个非常糟糕的失败模式
much every culture in history has had
历史上的每一种文化都有
some story along the same lines you know
你知道的一些故事
there's the the genie that gives you
有精灵给你
three wishes and you know third wish is
三个愿望 ，你知道第三个愿望是
always you know please undo the first
总是你 知道请撤消第一个
two wishes because I messed up
两个愿望，因为我搞砸了
and you know and when author Samuel
而且你知道什么时候作者塞缪尔
wrote his chest his checkup laying
他的胸部写了他的 检查铺设
program which learned to play checkers
学会玩跳棋的程序
considerably better than Martha Samuel
比玛莎 撒母耳好多了
could play and actually reached a pretty
可以玩，实际上达到了漂亮
decent standard
体面的标准
Norbert Wiener who was a one of the
Norbert Wiener是其中之一
major mathematicians of the 20th century
20世纪的主要数学家
sort of a father of modern automation
有点像现代自动化之父
control systems
控制系统
you know he saw this and he basically
你知道他基本上看到了这一点
extrapolated you know as Turing did and
外推你知道 图灵做了
said okay this is how we could lose
说好的， 这 就是我们失败的方式
control and specifically that we have to
控制，特别是我们必须
be certain that the purpose we put into
确定我们投入的目的
the machine as the purpose which we
机器是我们的目的
really desire and the problem is we
真正的愿望和问题是我们
can't do that right you mean we're not
不能这样做 你的 意思是我们不是
it's a very difficult to encode so to
这是一个 非常困难的编码， 所以
put our values on paper is really
把我们的价值观写在纸上真的是
difficult or you're just saying it's
很难，或者你只是 在说它
impossible your line is writing this so
不可能你行 这么 写 ，这
it's it theoretically it's possible but
理论上它是可能的，但是
in practice it's extremely unlikely that
在实践中这是极不可能的
we could specify correctly in advance
我们可以提前正确指定
the full range of concerns of humanity
全人类关注的人性问题
that you talked about cultural
你谈到 文化
transmission of values I think is how
传递价值我认为是如何
humans to human transmission of values
人类对人类传播 价值观
happens right what we learned yeah I
发生 在我们学到的东西 是的我
mean as we grow up we learn about the
意味着我们长大后会 了解到
values that matter how things how things
价值观重要的事情如何
should go what is reasonable to pursue
应该走什么是合理 的追求
and what isn't reasonable to pursue
什么是不合理的追求
machines can learn in the same kind of
机器可以在 同一种类型中 学习
way yeah so I think that what we need to
方式是啊所以我认为我们需要的
do is to get away from this idea that
做的是从 这个 想法 脱身 那
you build an optimizing machine and you
你和你建立一个优化机器
put the objective into it
把目标放进去
because if it's possible that you might
因为如果你可能的话
put in a wrong objective and we already
错误的目标，我们已经
know this is possible because it's
知道这是可能的， 因为它是
happened lots of times alright that
发生了很多次， 好吧
means that the machine should never take
意味着机器永远不应该采取
an objective that's given as gospel
一个作为福音给出的目标
truth
真相
because once it takes them the the
因为一旦它需要它们
objective is gospel truth alright then
目标是信以为真 好吧
it's the leaves that whatever actions
无论采取什么行动 ，它都是叶子
it's taking in pursuit of that objective
它正在追求这一目标
are the correct things to do so you
这是正确的事情你这样做
could be jumping up and down and saying
可能是跳来跳去说
no you know no no no you're gonna
不，你不知道不，不，你会
destroy the world but the machine knows
摧毁世界，但机器知道
what the true objective is and it's
真正的目标是什么，它是什么
pursuing it and tough luck to you you
它坚韧运气追求你，你
know and this is not restricted to AI
知道 ，这不仅限于人工智能
right this is you know I think many of
对，你知道我认为很多
the 20th century technologies right so
20世纪的技术是如此
in statistics you you minimize a loss
在统计数据中， 您可以减少损失
function the loss function is
功能损失功能是
exogenously specified in control theory
在控制理论中外源指定
you minimize a cost function in
你最小化成本 函数
operations research you maximize a
运营研究你最大化a
reward function and so on so in all
在所有的奖励功能等等等等
these disciplines this is how we
这些学科这就是我们的方式
conceive of the problem and it's the
设想问题就是这个问题
wrong problem because we cannot specify
错误的问题，因为我们无法指定
with certainty the correct objective
确定无误的正确 目标
right we need uncertainty we the machine
对，我们需要机器的不确定性
to be uncertain about a subjective what
不确定主观是什么
it is that it's post it's my favorite
这是它的 帖子，这是我 最喜欢的
idea of yours I've heard you say
你的想法我听说你说
somewhere well I shouldn't pick
在某个地方，我不应该选择
favorites but it just sounds beautiful
收藏，但它听起来很美
we need to teach machines humility yeah
我们需要教机器谦虚 是的
I mean it's a beautiful way to put it I
我的意思 是 把它放在我 一个美丽的方式
love it
喜欢它
that they humble oh yeah they know that
他们谦虚哦，是的，他们知道这一点
they don't know what it is they're
他们不知道 他们是什么
supposed to be doing and that those
应该做的事情 ，而 这些
those objectives I mean they exist they
那些目标我的意思是他们存在
are within us but we may not be able to
不到我们 ，但我们可能无法
explicate them we may not even know you
说明他们我们可能 甚至 不 认识你
know how we want our future to go so
知道我们希望我们的未来如何发展
exactly and the Machine you know a
确切地说， 你知道的机器
machine that's uncertain he's going to
机器，他不确定他会去
be deferential to us so if we say don't
如果我们不说，请恭敬我们
do that well now the machines learn
现在这些机器学得很好
something a bit more about our true
更多关于我们真实的东西
objectives because something that it
目标，因为它的东西
thought was reasonable in pursuit of our
为了追求我们的想法是合理的
objectives turns out not to be so now
目标结果并非如此
it's learn something so it's going to
它会 学到一些东西， 所以它会 发生
defer because it wants to be doing what
推迟，因为 它希望 做什么
we really want
我们真的想要
and you know that that point I think is
你知道我认为这一点
absolutely central to solving the
绝对是解决问题的关键
control problem and it's a different
控制问题，这是一个不同的
kind of AI when you when you take away
一种 人工智能 的 时候 你们什么时候拿走
this idea that the objective is known
这个目标是众所周知的
then in fact a lot of the theoretical
那实际上很多理论上的
frameworks that we're so familiar with
我们那么熟悉框架
you know Markov decision processes goal
你知道马尔可夫的决策过程目标
based planning you know standard games
基于规划 你知道标准游戏
research all of these techniques
研究所有这些技术
actually become inapplicable and you get
实际上变得不适用而且你得到了
a more complicated problem because
一个更复杂的问题，因为
because now the interaction with the
因为现在用的相互作用
human becomes part of the problem
人类成为问题的一部分
because the human by making choices is
因为人类通过做出选择是
giving you more information about the
为您提供有关的更多信息
'true objective and that information
'真正的目标和那些 信息
helps you achieve the objective better
帮助您更好地实现目标
and so that really means that you're
所以这真的 意味着你
mostly dealing with game theoretic
主要是处理游戏理论
problems where you've got the machine
你有机器的问题
and the human and they're coupled
和人类，他们是耦合的
together rather than a machine going off
一起而不是机器 起飞
by itself with a fixed objective which
本身就有一个固定的目标
is fascinating on the machine and the
对机器和机器 很有吸引力
human level that we when you don't have
当你 没有 时我们的人类水平
an objective means you're together
客观意味着你在一起
coming up with an objective I mean
提出一个 我的意思 的目标
there's a lot of philosophy that you
有很多的哲学 ，你
know you could argue that life doesn't
知道你可以说生命 没有
really have meaning we we together agree
真的有意义我们在一起 同意
on what gives it meaning and we kind of
什么赋予它意义，我们有点
culturally create things that give why
从文化上创造出能够解释原因的东西
the heck we are in this earth anyway we
无论如何， 我们在这个世界上
together as a society create that
作为一个社会共同创造
meaning and you have to learn that
意思，你必须要学习
objective and one of the biggest I
客观和最大的我之一
thought that's what you were gonna go
以为这就是你要去的地方
for a second
一秒钟
one of the biggest troubles we've run
我们遇到的最大麻烦之一
into outside of statistics and machine
进入统计和机器之外
learning and AI and just human
学习和人工智能，只是人类
civilization is when you look at I came
文明是你看我来的时候
from the south was born in the Soviet
从 南出生 于苏联
Union and the history of the 20th
联盟和20世纪的历史
century we ran into the most trouble us
世纪我们遇到了最麻烦的我们
humans when there was a certainty about
人类何时有确定性
the objective and you do whatever it
目标，你做任何事情
takes to achieve that objective whether
是否 实现了这一 目标
you talking about in Germany or
你在德国谈论或
communist Russia oh yeah I get the
共产主义俄罗斯噢，我得到了
trouble I would say with you know
麻烦，我会 跟你说
corporations in fact some people argue
事实上有些人争辩说公司
that you know we don't have to look
你知道我们 不必看
forward to a time when AI systems take
转发到 AI系统 的时代
over the world they already have and
在他们已经拥有的世界上
they call corporations right that
他们称公司是正确的
corporations happen to be using people
公司碰巧使用人
as components right now but they are
现在作为组件， 但他们是
effectively algorithmic machines and
有效的算法机器和
they're optimizing an objective which is
他们正在优化一个目标
quarterly profit that isn't aligned with
季度利润不符合
overall well-being of the human race and
人类 和 人类的总体福祉
they are destroying the world they are
他们正在摧毁他们的世界
primarily responsible for our inability
主要负责我们的 无能
to tackle climate change right so I
应对气候变化的权利，所以我
think that's one way
认为这是一种方式
of thinking about what's going on with
思考发生了什么
with cooperations but I think the point
合作但我认为重点
you're making you is valid that there
你让你在那里有效
are there are many systems in the real
是 真的 有 很多系统吗？
world where we've sort of prematurely
我们有点过早的世界
fixed on the objective and then
固定在目标上然后
decoupled the the machine from those
从那些解耦的机器
that's supposed to be serving and I
应该是服务和 我
think you see this with government right
认为你看到政府的 权利
government is supposed to be a machine
政府应该是一台机器
that serves people but instead it tends
这为人们服务，但相反，它倾向于
to be taken over by people who have
被拥有的人接管
their own objective and use government
他们自己的目标和使用政府
to optimize that objective regardless of
无论如何都要优化这个目标
what people want do you have do you find
人们想要的 是 你找到的
appealing the idea of almost arguing
吸引几乎争论的想法
machines where you have multiple I
你 有多个 I的机器
systems with a clear fixed objective we
我们有明确固定目标的系统
have in government the red team and the
在政府中 有红队和
blue team that are very fixed on their
蓝队 是非常固定在 其
objectives and they argue and it kind of
目标和他们争论 ，它有点
maybe it would disagree but it kind of
也许它会不同意但有点像
seems to make it work somewhat that the
似乎使它 有点 工作
the duality of it okay let's go a
它的二元性好吧，让我们去吧
hundred years back when there was still
百年回来的时候还有
was going on or at the founding of this
正在进行或正在建立 这个
country there was disagreement and that
国家有 分歧和那个
disagreement is where so there's a
分歧是 在哪里，所以有一个
balance between certainty and forced
在确定性和被迫之间取得平衡
humility because the power was
谦卑， 因为力量
distributed yeah I think that the the
分发是啊我认为
the nature of debate and disagreement
辩论和分歧的本质
argument takes as a premise the idea
参数使用为前提的想法
that you could be wrong right which
那你可能是 错的
means that you're not necessarily
意味着你 不一定
absolutely convinced that your objective
绝对相信你的 目标
is the correct one right if you were
如果你是 正确的，那就是正确 的
absolutely Guiness there'll be no point
绝对吉尼斯没有意义
in having any discussion or argument
在进行任何讨论或论证
because you would never change your mind
因为你永远不会改变主意
and there wouldn't be any any sort of
并且不会有任何形式的
synthesis or or anything like that so so
合成或之类的东西，以便使
I think you can think of argumentation
我想你可以 想到论证
as a as an implementation of a form of
作为作为一种形式的实施方案
uncertain reasoning
不确定的推理
and you know I I've been reading
你知道我 我一直在读
recently about utilitarianism in the
最近关于功利主义的
history of efforts to define in a sort
努力定义的历史
of clear mathematical way a
明确的数学方法
I feel like a formula for moral or
我觉得这是道德或道德的公式
political decision-making and it's
政治决策和它
really interesting that the parallels
非常有趣的是相似之处
between the philosophical discussions
在哲学讨论之间
going back 200 years and what you see
回到200 年，你看到了什么
now in discussions about existential
现在正在讨论存在主义
risk because you it's almost exactly the
风险，因为你几乎完全是
same so someone would say okay well
同样 有人会说好的
here's a formula for how we should make
这是我们应该如何制作的公式
decisions right so utilitarianism
决定权利所以功利主义
you know each person has a utility
你知道每个人都有一个实用工具
function and then we make decisions to
功能，然后我们做出决定
maximize the sum of everybody's utility
最大化每个人的效用之和
mm-hmm right and then people point out
mm-hmm对，然后人们指出
well you know in that case the best
那么你在这种 情况下，最好知道
policy is one that leads to the enormous
政策是导致巨大的政策
lis vast population all of whom are
LIS庞大的人口 他们都是
living a life that's barely worth living
过着的生活，是 根本不值得活
right and this is called the repugnant
对，这被称为令人反感
conclusion and you know another version
结论，你知道另一个版本
is you know that we we should maximize
你知道我们应该最大化吗？
pleasure and that's what we mean by
快乐， 这就是我们的意思
utility and then you'll get people
效用，然后你会得到人
effectively saying well in that case you
在那种情况下你有效地说得好
know we might as well just have everyone
知道我们也许只有每个人
hooked up to a heroin drip yeah you know
迷上海洛因滴，是的，你知道吗
and they didn't use those words but that
他们没有使用那些词语 但
debate you know what's happening in the
辩论 你知道发生了什么
19th century as it is now about AI that
19 世纪，因为它现在关于人工智能
if we get the formula wrong you know
如果我们弄错了公式，你知道
we're going to have AI systems working
我们将要有AI系统 工作
towards an outcome that in retrospect
朝着回想起来的结果
would be exactly wrong do you think
会完全错了，你认为
there's it has beautifully put so the
它有这么漂亮
the echoes are there but do you think I
回声在那里，但你认为我
mean if you look at sam Harris is our
如果你看看山姆哈里斯是我们的意思
imagination worries about the AI version
想象力担心AI版本
of that because of the speed at which
由于 速度的原因
the things going wrong in the
事情出了问题
utilitarian context could happen yeah is
功利主义背景可能发生是的
that is that a worry for you yeah I I
那就是你啊，我 我 一个担心
think that
认为
you know it in most cases not in all but
你知道在大多数情况下并非如此
you know if we if we have a wrong
你知道我们 是否 有错
political idea you know we see it
你知道我们看到 它的 政治观念
starting to go wrong and we're you know
开始出错 ， 我们就是你知道的
we're not completely stupid and so we
我们并非完全愚蠢，所以我们
said okay that was maybe that was a
说没关系 ， 也许那是一个
mistake
错误
let's try something different and and
让我们尝试不同的东西，并和
also we're very slow and inefficient
我们也 非常缓慢而且效率低下
about implementing these things and so
关于实现这些事情等等
on so you have to worry when you have
在所以你必须在你不必担心
corporations or political systems that
公司或政治制度
are extremely efficient
非常有效率
but when we look at AI systems or even
但是当我们看到AI系统甚至是
just computers in general right they
只是电脑一般对他们
have this different characteristic from
有这个不同的特点
ordinary human activity in the past so
过去普通的人类活动
let's say you were a surgeon you had
让我们说你是 你有 一个外科医生
some idea about how to do some operation
关于如何 做一些操作的一些想法
right well and let's say you were wrong
好吧，让我们说你错了
all right that that way of doing the
那样 做的 那种方式
operation would mostly kill the patient
手术将主要杀死病人
well you'd find out pretty quickly like
好吧，你很快就会发现
after three maybe three or four tries
经过三次或三次或四次尝试
right
对
but
但
that isn't true for pharmaceutical
对于制药而言并非如此
companies because they don't do three or
公司， 因为他们不做三 或
four operations they they manufacture
他们制造的 四个 操作
three or four billion pills and they
三四十亿丸和它们
sell them and then they find out maybe
出售他们，然后他们发现可能
six months or a year later that oh
半年或一年 后，即 哦
people are dying of heart attacks or
人们正在心脏病发作 或 死亡
getting cancer from this drug and so
从这种药物中获得癌症等等
that's why we have the FDA right because
这就是我们拥有FDA 权利的原因所在
of the scalability of pharmaceutical
药品的可扩展性
production and you know and there have
生产，你知道，有
been some unbelievably bad episodes in
是一些令人难以置信的糟糕剧集
the history of pharmaceuticals and and
药品的历史， 和
adulteration of of products and so on
掺假产品 等
that that have killed tens of thousands
已经杀死了数万人
or paralysed hundreds of thousands of
或瘫痪数十万
people now with computers we have that
人们现在有了电脑我们就有 了
same scalability problem that you can
您可以使用相同的可扩展性问题
sit there and type for I equals 1 to 5
坐在那里， 输入I等于1到5
billion do right and all of a sudden
十亿人做 对了，突然之间
you're having an impact on a global
你有在 全球 的影响
scale and yet we have no FDA right
规模，但我们 没有FDA的 权利
there's absolutely no controls at all
完全没有控制权
it's over what a bunch of undergraduates
它取决于一群本科生
with too much caffeine can do to the
含有过多咖啡因可以做到
world and you know we look at what
世界，你 知道我们看什么
happened with Facebook well social media
发生在Facebook社交媒体上
in general and click-through
一般而言，点击进入
optimization so you have a simple
优化让你有一个简单的
feedback algorithm that's trying to just
这正试图 只是 反馈算法
optimize click-through that sounds
优化单击， 通过 声音
reasonable right because you don't want
合理的权利，因为你不想要
to be feeding people ads that they don't
向人们提供他们没有的广告
care about I'm not interested in
关心我 不感兴趣
and you might even think of that process
你甚至可能会想到这个过程
as simply adjusting the the feeding of
简单地调整喂养
ads or news articles or whatever it
广告或 新闻文章或其他任何内容
might be to match people's preferences
可能是为了匹配人们的偏好
right which sounds like a good idea but
这听起来是个好 主意 但是
in fact that isn't how the algorithm
实际上那不是算法怎么样
works right you make more money the
你工作得更赚钱了
algorithm makes more money if it could
算法使更多的钱，如果它 可以
better predict what people are going to
更好地预测哪些人会
click on because then it can feed them
点击 它，因为它可以喂它们
exactly that right so the way to
正是如此，所以通往
maximize click-through is actually to
最大限度地提高点击率实际上是
modify the people to make them more
修改人员以使他们更多
predictable and one way to do that is to
可预测的，一种方法 是做到这一点
feed them information which will change
向他们提供将要改变的信息
their behavior and preferences towards
他们的行为和偏好
extremes that make them predictable now
现在可以预测它们的极端情况
whatever is the nearest extreme or the
什么是最近的极端或
nearest predictable point that's where
最近的可预测点 就在哪里
you're going to end up
你最终会结束
the machines will force you there now
机器现在会迫使你到那里
and then I think there's a reasonable
然后我认为这是合理的
argument to say that this among other
论点 说，这 等 中
things is contributing to the
事情正在协助
destruction of democracy in the world
民主 的毁灭世界
and where was the oversight of this
哪里是这种监督
process where were the people saying
过程人们在哪里说
okay you would like to apply this
好的， 你想申请这个
algorithm to five billion people on the
算法让 五十亿 人上了
face of the earth can you show me that
你可以告诉我那个 地球的面貌
it's safe can you show me that it won't
你能安全地告诉 我 它不会
have various kinds of negative effects
有各种各样 的 负面影响
no there was no one asking that question
没有 人问这个问题
there was no one placed between you know
你知道之间没有人放置
the undergrads were too much caffeine
本科生的咖啡因太多了
and the human race well it's just they
和人类一样，这就是他们
just did it and but some way outside the
只是做到了， 但外面 的 一些方法
scope of my knowledge so economists
我的知识范围如此经济学家
would argue that the what is it the
会争辩说它是什么
invisible hand so the the capitalist
看不见的 手所以资本家
system
系统
it was the oversight so if you're going
这是疏忽，所以如果你要去
to corrupt society with whatever
以任何方式腐败社会
decision you make is a company then
你做出的决定是一家公司
that's going to be reflected in people
这将反映在人们身上
not using your product sort of one
不使用你的产品
that's one model of oversight so we
这是一种疏忽模式，所以我们
shall see but you know in the meantime
应该看到， 但 在此期间你知道
you know that but you you might even
你知道，但你甚至可能
have broken the political system that
已经打破了政治制度
enables capitalism to function well
使资本主义运作良好
you've changed it and so we should see
你改变了它，所以我们应该看到
yeah change changes often painful so my
是的改变经常是痛苦所以我的
question is uh absolutely it's
问题是，绝对是的
fascinating
迷人
you're absolutely right that there is
你是 绝对正确 的有
ZERO oversight on algorithms that can
ZERO 可以 对 算法 进行监督
have a profound civilization changing
有一个深刻的文明变化
effect so do you think it's possible I
效果所以你 认为我有可能
mean I haven't have you seen government
意思是我没有你 见过政府
so do you think it's possible to create
那么你认为这是 可能 创造
regulatory bodies oversight over AI
监管机构监督AI
algorithms which are inherently such
本质上就是这样的算法
cutting edge set of ideas and
尖端的一套想法和
technologies yeah but I think it takes
技术是的，但我认为这需要
time
时间
to figure out what kind of oversight
弄清楚是什么样的疏忽
what kinds of controls I mean took time
我的意思是什么样的控制需要时间
to design the FDA regime you know and
设计你知道的FDA制度
some people still don't like it and they
有些人仍然不喜欢它和他们
want to fix it
想要解决它
and I think there are clear ways that it
而且我认为它有 明确的方法
could be improved but the whole notion
可以改善，但 整个概念
that you have stage 1 stage 2 stage 3
你有阶段1 阶段2阶段3
and here are the criteria for what you
这是 你 的 标准
have to do to pass a stage 1 trial right
必须做的就是通过第 1 阶段的 试验
we haven't even thought about what those
我们甚至没有想过 那些
would be
会
for algorithms so I mean I think there
对于算法， 所以我的意思是我认为 那里
are there are things we could do right
有没有 我们可以做的事情
now with regard to bias for example we
现在关于偏见，例如我们
we have a pretty good technical handle
我们有很好的技术手段
on how to detect algorithms that are
如何检测 是 算法
propagating bias that exists in data
传播数据中存在的偏见
sets how to D by us those algorithms and
我们将这些算法和算法 设置 为D
and even what it's going to cost you to
甚至是你要 付出的代价
do that so I think we could start having
做到这一点，所以我想我们可以开始 有
some standards on that I think there are
我认为有一些标准
there are things to do with
有一些事情要做
impersonation of falsification that we
模仿我们的伪造
could we could work on so I thanks ya or
我们可以继续努力，所以我 感谢 你 或者
you know in a very simple point so
你在一个 很简单的 一点知道，所以
impersonation ISM is a machine acting as
模仿ISM是一台 充当 的机器
if it was a person I can't see a real
如果是一个人， 我看不到真实
justification for why we shouldn't
为什么我们不应该这样做的理由
insist that machines self-identify as
坚持认为机器是自我认同的
machines you know where is the social
机器你知道社交在哪里
benefit in in fooling people into
愚弄人们的利益
thinking that this is really a person
以为这真的 是一个人
when it isn't you know I I don't mind if
当你不 知道的时候我不介意
it uses a human-like voice that's easy
它使用类似人类的声音，这很容易
to understand that's fine
明白这很好
but it should just say I'm a machine in
但它应该说我是一台机器
some some form
一些形式
people are speaking to that I would
人说话，我会
think relatively obvious factors I think
认为我认为相对明显的 因素
mostly yeah I mean there is actually a
主要是的，我的意思 是实际上有一个
law in California that bans
禁止加利福尼亚的法律
impersonation but only in certain
冒充， 但只有在某些情况下
restricted circumstances so for the
受限制的情况因此
purpose of engaging in a for Geling
在从事了严歌苓的目的
transaction and for the purpose of
交易和目的
modifying someone's voting behavior so
修改别人的投票行为，
those are those are the circumstances
那些是那些情况
where machines have to self-identify but
机器必须自我识别 但是
I think this is you know arguably it
我想 这就是你所知道的
should be in all circumstances and then
应该在所有情况下然后
when you talk about deep fakes you know
当你谈到你知道的 深度假货
we're just beginning but already it's
我们刚刚开始，但已经是它了
possible to make a movie of anybody
可以制作任何人 的 电影
saying anything in ways that are pretty
用漂亮的方式说什么
hard to detect including yourself
很难察觉 包括 你自己
because you're on camera now and your
因为你现在和 你的 相机
voice is coming through with high
声音高涨
resolution so you could take what I'm
分辨率， 所以 你 可以采取 我的意思
saying and replaces it with it pretty
说，并用 它 替换 它漂亮
much anything else you wanted me to be
你想要我做的任何其他事情
saying yeah and even it will change my
说是的， 甚至会改变我的
lips and expression expressions to fit
嘴唇和表情表达适合
and there's actually not much in the way
并且实际上并没有太多的 方式
of real legal protection against that I
对我的真正法律保护
think in the commercial area you could
想想你在商业领域
say yeah that's you're using my brand
说是的， 你在使用我的品牌
and so on that there there are rules
等等， 那里有规则
about that but in the political sphere I
关于这一点，但在 政治领域 我
think it's at the moment it's you know
认为这是它是 你知道 的 那一刻
anything goes so like that could be
任何事情都可能如此
really really damaging and let me just
真的非常有害，让我公正
try to make not an argument but try to
试着不是争论 而是试着
look back at history and say something
回顾历史，说些什么
dark in essence is while regulation
黑暗本质上是在监管时
seems to be oversight seems to be
似乎是疏忽似乎是
exactly the right thing to do here
在这里做正确的事情
it seems that human beings what they
看来人类是什么样的人
naturally do is they wait for something
他们自然会做的是等待什么
to go wrong if you're talking about
去，如果你谈论的 是 错误的
nuclear weapons
核武器
you can't talk about nuclear weapons
你不能谈论核武器
being dangerous until somebody actually
直到某人实际上是危险的
like the United States drops the bomb or
就像美国放下炸弹一样
Chernobyl melting do you think we will
切尔诺贝利融化你认为我们会
have to wait for things going wrong in a
必须等待一件事情出错
way that's obviously damaging to society
这显然对社会有害
not an existential risk but obviously
不是存在风险，但显然
damaging or do you have faith that I I
伤害或你是否相信II
hope not but I mean I think we do have
希望不是，但我的 意思是我认为我们确实 有
to look at history and when you know so
看看历史，当 你 知道的时候
the two examples you gave nuclear
你 给核的两个例子
weapons and nuclear power are very very
武器和核能非常非常
interesting because you know in nuclear
有趣， 因为你知道核
weapons we knew in the early years of
武器，我们知道，在早年 的
the 20th century that atoms contained a
原子包含的20世纪
huge amount of energy right we had e
我们拥有的巨大能量权利e
equals mc-squared we knew the the mass
等于mc-squared我们知道 质量
differences between the different atoms
不同原子之间的差异
and their components and we knew that
和他们的组件，我们知道
you might be able to make an incredibly
你可能会 做出令人难以置信的
powerful explosive so HG Wells wrote
强大的爆发力，所以HG威尔斯写道
science fiction book I think in 1912
我认为 1912年的 科幻小说
Frederick Soddy who was the guy who
弗雷德里克索迪是谁的家伙
discovered isotopes so Nobel Prize
发现同位素所以诺贝尔奖
winner he gave a speech in 1915 saying
获奖者他于1915年发表演讲
that
那
this new explosive would be the
这种新的爆炸物将是
equivalent of 150 tons of dynamite which
相当于150 吨的炸药
turns out to be about right and you know
原来是对的 ，你知道
Kenton this was in World War one right
肯顿这是在第一次世界大战中的权利
so he was imagining how much worse the
所以他想象的更糟糕 了
world would be if we were using that
如果我们使用它，世界就会如此
kind of explosive but the physics
有点 爆炸但物理
establishment simply refused to believe
建立只是拒绝相信
that these things could be made
这些东西都可以制造出来
including the people who are making it
包括谁正在它 的人
well so they were doing the nuclear
好吧，他们正在做核
physics I mean eventually were the ones
物理学我的意思最终是那些
who made it and Rockwell for me or
是谁和罗克韦尔为我或
whoever well so up to the the
谁 也因此到了
development was was mostly theoretical
发展主要是理论上的
so it was people using sort of primitive
所以人们使用的是原始的
kinds of particle acceleration and doing
各种粒子加速和做
experiments at the at the level of
在水平上的实验
single particles or collections of
单个粒子或集合
particles they they they want
他们想要的粒子
yet thinking about how to actually make
还在思考如何实际制作
a bomb or anything like that they but
炸弹或类似的东西，但他们
they knew the energy was there and they
他们知道能量存在于他们身上
figured if they understood it better it
想通，如果他们了解它越好
might be possible but the physics
有可能，但 物理
establishment their view and I think
建立他们的观点， 我认为
because they did not want it to be true
因为他们 不希望 它 是真的
their view was that it could not be true
他们认为这不可能 是 真的
that this could not provide a way to
这不能 提供一种方式来
make a super weapon and you know there
做一个超级武器 ，你知道 有
was this famous speech given by
是这个着名的演讲
Rutherford who was the sort of leader of
卢瑟福是那种领导者
nuclear physics and I was on September
核物理和我在九月
11th 1933 and he he said you know anyone
1933年11月，他说你认识任何人
who talks about the possibility of
谁约的 可能性会谈
obtaining energy from transformation of
从转型中获取能量
atoms is talking complete moonshine and
原子正在谈论完全的月光和
the next the next morning Leo Szilard
接下来的第二天早上 利奥 ·西拉德
read about that speech and then invented
阅读该演讲然后发明
the nuclear chain reaction and so as
核链反应等
soon as he invented he soon as he had
他 很快就 发明了他
that idea that you could make a chain
这个想法， 你可以建立一个链
reaction with neutrons because neutrons
与中子反应，因为中子
were not repelled by the nucleus so they
不是由原子核所以他们击退
could enter the nucleus and then
然后可以进入细胞核
continue the reaction as soon as he has
他一有这个就继续做出反应
that idea he instantly realized that the
那个想法他立即意识到了
world was in deep doo-doo because this
因为 这个世界在深深的doo-doo
is 1933 right you know Hitler had
是1933年， 你知道希特勒
recently come to power in Germany
最近在德国上台
Zil odd was in London and eventually
齐尔奇 最终在伦敦
became a refugee and and came to the US
成为难民，并来到美国
and the in the process of having the
并且在拥有的过程中
idea about the chain reaction he figured
关于 他认为 的连锁反应的想法
out basically how to make a bomb and
基本上如何制作炸弹和
also how to make a reactor and he
还有如何 制造一个反应堆和他
patented the reactor
反应器专利
2:34 but because of the situation the
的 2:34 但是因为情况
great power conflict situation that he
他的大国冲突局势
could see happening he kept that a
可以看到发生了他保持这一点
secret and so between then and the
之间 和 之间的秘密等等
beginning of World War two people were
第二次世界大战开始的时候
working including the Germans on how to
包括 德国人如何工作
actually create Neutron sources right
实际创建中子源 权
what specific fission reactions would
什么具体的裂变反应会
produce neutrons of the right energy to
产生合适能量的中子
continue the reaction and and that was
继续反应 ，那就是
demonstrated in Germany I think in 1938
我想在1938年在德国证明了这一点
if I remember correctly the first
如果我没记错第一个
nuclear weapon patent was 1939 by the
核武器专利是1939年由
French so this was actually you know
法语所以这实际上是你知道的
this was actually
这实际上是
going on you know well before World War
在第二次世界大战前你就知道了
two really got going and then you know
两个真的开始 然后你知道
the British probably had the most
英国人可能拥有的最多
advanced capability in this area but for
这方面的先进能力，但是
safety reasons among others and blush
其他安全原因和脸红
which is sort of just resources they
这只是他们的资源
moved the program from Britain to the US
将该计划从 英国 转移到了 美国
and then that became Manhattan Project
然后那就成了曼哈顿计划
so the the the reason why we couldn't
所以 我们不能 这样做的 原因
have any kind of oversight of nuclear
对核 有任何形式 的监督
weapons and nuclear technology was
武器和核技术是
because we were basically already in an
因为我们基本上已经在
arms race in a war and but you you've
在战争中的军备竞赛， 但你，你
mentioned then in the 20s and 30s so
那么在20和 30年代就提到了
what are the echoes yeah the way you've
是什么回声是 你的方式
described this story I mean there's
描述这个故事我的意思是
clearly echoes why do you think most a I
清楚地 回应为什么你 认为我最喜欢的
researchers
研究人员
folks who are really close to the metal
那些非常接近金属的人
they really are not concerned about it
他们真的不关心它
and they don't think about it
他们 没有想到 这一点
whether they don't want to think about
他们是否不想去想
it it's but what are the yeah why do you
它是什么，但是你为什么这么做
think that is what are the echoes of the
认为那是什么回声
nuclear situation to the current
目前的 核 情况
situation and what can we do about it I
情况 ，我们可以做些什么 呢？
think there is a you know a kinda modak
认为 你知道 有一种 模式
motivated cognition which is a term in
积极的认知，这是一个术语
psychology means that you believe what
心理学意味着你相信什么
you would like to be true rather than
你想成为真实的而不是
what is true and you know it's it's
什么是真的 ，你知道它就是它
unsettling to think that what you're
不安地想到你是什么
working on might be the end of the human
工作可能是 人类 结束
race obviously so you would rather
种族显然所以你宁愿
instantly deny it
立即否认它
and come up with some reason why it
并提出一些 原因
couldn't be true and the you know I have
不可能是真的，你知道 我有
I collected a long list of reasons that
我收集了很多原因
extremely intelligent competent AI
非常智能的 AI
scientists have come up with for why we
科学家们为 我们提出了 原因
shouldn't worry about this you know for
不要担心你知道的
example calculators are super human at
示例计算器是 超人类的
arithmetic and they haven't taken over
算术，他们 没有接管
the world so there's nothing to worry
世界所以没有什么 可担心的
about well okay my five-year-old you
关于 我 五岁的 你 好吧
know could have figured out why that was
知道可能已经弄明白为什么会这样
an unreasonable and and really quite
一个不合理的 ， 而且非常的
weak argument you know another one was
你知道另一个人的弱论点
you know you while it's theoretically
从理论上讲，你了解你
possible that you could have superhuman
可能你 有超人
AI destroy the world you know it's also
AI 毁灭世界，你知道它 也是
theoretically possible that a black hole
理论上可能是 黑洞
could materialize right next to the
可以在 旁边实现
earth and destroy humanity I mean yes
地球和摧毁人类我的意思是肯定的
it's theoretically possible quantum
这在理论上是可能的量子
theoretically extremely unlikely that it
理论上它不太可能
would just materialize right there but
会在 那里实现但是
that's a completely bogus analogy
这是一个完全虚假的比喻
because you know if the whole physics
因为你知道整个物理学
community on earth was working to
地球上的社区正在努力
materialize a black hole in near Earth
在地球附近形成一个黑洞
orbit right wouldn't you ask them is
轨道权利你不会问他们
that a good idea is that gonna be safe
这是 一个好 主意是， 会是 安全的
you know what if you succeed all right
你知道如果你成功了会怎么样
right and that's the thing right the AI
权，这是正确 的AI的东西
is sort of refused to ask itself what if
有点拒绝问自己如果
you succeed and initially I think that
你成功和最初我认为，
was because it was too hard but you know
是因为它太难了但你知道
Alan Turing asked himself that and he
艾伦·图灵问自己和他
said we'd be toast right if we were
我们说如果我们的话，我们会干得 好
lucky we might be able to switch off the
幸运的是我们可以关掉
power but probably we'd be toast but
力量 但可能我们会敬酒但是
there's also an aspect that because
还有一个方面， 因为
we're not exactly sure what the future
我们不确定 未来会是 什么
holds it's not clear exactly so
认为它并不清楚
technically what to worry about sort of
技术上有什么担心的
how things go wrong and so there is
事情出了问题，所以有
something it feels like maybe you can
感觉就像你可以
correct me if I'm wrong but there's
如果我错了，请 纠正 我但是有
something paralyzing about worrying
令人担忧的事情让人沮丧
about something that logically is
关于逻辑上的东西
inevitable but you don't really know
不可避免，但你真的不知道
what that will look like yeah I think
我认为那会是什么样子
that's that's it's a reasonable point
这就是合理的一点
and you know the you know it's certainly
而且你知道你知道它肯定
in terms of existential risks it's
就存在风险而言
different from you know asteroid
不同于你知道的小行星
collides with the earth right right
与地球右右碰撞
which again is quite possible you know
你 知道这很可能
it's happened in the past it'll probably
它可能发生在过去
happen again we don't right we don't
再次发生我们不对，我们没有
know right now but if we did detect an
现在知道， 但 如果我们确实检测到了
asteroid that was going to hit the earth
小行星即将袭击地球
in 75 years time we'd certainly be doing
在75年的时间里，我们肯定会这样做
something about it well it's clear
关于它的一些事情很清楚
there's got big rocks we'll probably
我们 可能 会有大 石头
have a meeting you see what do we do
开会，你看我们做了什么
about the big rock
关于大石头
will they I write with a I I mean the
他们将我与 II 写 的 意思 是
very few people who think it's not gonna
很少有人认为这不会
happen within the next 75 years
在接下来的75 年内发生
I know rod Brooks doesn't think it's
我知道布鲁克斯不认为这是
gonna happen maybe and ruing doesn't
也许 会发生 ， 而ruing则不会
think it's happened but you know a lot
认为它发生了， 但你知道很多
of the people who work day-to-day you
谁的工作一天到一天的人 你
know as you say at the rock face
就像你在岩壁上说的那样
they think it's gonna happen I think the
他们认为这 会发生我认为
median estimate from AI researchers is
AI研究人员的中位数估计是
somewhere in forty to fifty years from
从四十到五十年的某个地方
from now or maybe a little you know I
从现在开始，或许有点你知道我
think in Asia they think it's gonna be
他们认为在亚洲他们 认为会是这样
even faster than that I am I'm a little
甚至 比 我 更快 我也是一点点
bit more conservative I think probably
我觉得 可能有点保守
take longer than that but I think it's
需要更长时间 ，但我认为 是
you know as happened with nuclear
你知道就像核一样
weapons
武器
well I went overnight it can happen
好吧，我一夜之间就可以发生
overnight that you have these
一夜之间，你有这些
breakthroughs and we need more than one
突破，我们需要不止一个
breakthrough but you know the it's on
突破， 但你知道它是在
the order of half a dozen this is a very
这是一个非常好的 半打的顺序
rough scale but so half a dozen
粗糙的规模但是这么半打
breakthroughs of that nature it would
它会有这种性质的突破
have to happen for us to reach the
必须发生在 我们 身上
superhuman AI but the you know the AI
超人AI但是你知道AI
research community is vast now the
研究界现在很大
massive investments from governments
政府的大量投资
from corporations tons of really really
来自企业真的很多
smart people you know you just have to
聪明的 人，你知道你只需要
look at the rate of progress in
看看进步的速度
different areas of AI to see that things
AI的不同领域看到的东西
are moving pretty fast so to say oh it's
移动得非常快，所以 说哦
just gonna be thousands of years I don't
我要做 几千年 才不会
see any basis for that you know I see
看到你知道我看到的任何基础
you know for example the the Stanford
你知道斯坦福大学
hundred year AI project right which is
百年AI项目 是谁的权利
supposed to be sort of you know the
应该是你知道的那种
serious establishment view their most
认真建立最重要的观点
recent report actually said it's
最近的报道 实际上是这样说的
probably not even possible
可能甚至 不可能
Wow right which if you want a perfect
哇，如果你想要 完美的话
example of people in denial
例如人在 否认
that's it because you know for the whole
就是这样， 因为你知道整体
history of AI we've been saying to
人工智能的历史，我们一直在说
philosophers who said it wasn't possible
那些说不可能的哲学家
well you have no idea what you're
嗯，你不知道你是什么
talking about of course it's possible
谈论当然有可能
right give me an give me an argument for
对，给我 一个给我一个 论据
why it couldn't happen and there isn't
为什么它 不可能发生而且没有
one all right and now because people are
一个人好，现在因为 人
worried that maybe a oh it might get a
担心也许是哦它可能会得到 一个
bad name or or I just don't want to
坏名字或者或者我 只是不想
think about this they're saying okay
想想 这个，他们说的没问题
well of course it's not really possible
当然，这不太 可能
you know and we imagine right imagine if
你知道，我们 想象如果正确的想象
you know the the leaders of the cancer
你知道癌症的领导者
biology community got up and said well
生物界起身说 得好
you know of course curing cancer it's
你当然知道治愈癌症了
not really possible complete outrage and
真的不可能 完全愤怒 和
dismay and you know I I find this really
沮丧，你知道我发现这真的
a strange phenomenon so okay so if you
一个奇怪的现象，所以如果 你好
accept it as possible
尽可能地接受它
and if you accept that it's probably
如果你接受 它可能
going to happen
会 发生的
the point that you're making that you
你是在做那件事
know how does it go wrong a valid
知道它是如何出错的
question without that without an answer
没有 答案 就没有问题的问题
to that question then you stuck with
对 这个问题，那么 你坚持
what I call the gorilla problem which is
我所说的 大猩猩问题，就是
you know the problem that the gorillas
你知道大猩猩的问题
face right they made something more
面对他们，他们做了 更多
intelligent than them namely us a few
智能比他们就是我们 几
million years ago and now now they're in
百万年前，现在他们现在
deep doo-doo yeah so there's really
深doo-doo 是的，所以真的
nothing they can do they've lost the
他们无能为力，他们已经失去了
control theater they failed to solve the
控制剧院他们 未能解决问题
control problem of controlling humans
控制控制人类的问题
and so they've lost so we don't want to
他们已经失去了所以我们不想这样做
be in that situation and if the gorillas
在那种情况下，如果是大猩猩
problem is is the only formulation you
问题是你唯一的表述
have there's not a lot you can do right
有有不是很多，你可以 做 什么
other than to say okay we should try to
除了说好，我们应该 尝试
stop you know we should just not make
阻止你知道我们应该不做
the humans or right in this case not
在这种情况下人类或权利不是
make the AI and I think that's really
制作人工智能，我认为这是真的
hard to do
难做
- I'm not actually proposing that that's
- 我实际上并没有提出那个问题
a feasible course of action I also think
我也认为可行的行动方案
that you know if properly control a I
你知道如果恰当地控制了我
could be incredibly beneficial so the
可能是非常 有益的，所以
but it seems to me that there's a
但在我看来，有一个
there's a consensus that one of the
有一个共识， 其中一个
major failure modes is this loss of
主要的失败模式是这种损失
control that we create AI systems that
控制我们 创建的AI系统
are pursuing incorrect objectives and
正在追求不正确的目标和
because the AI system believes it knows
因为AI 系统相信它知道
what the objective is it has no
目标是 什么没有
incentive to listen to us anymore
鼓励我们再听一听
so to speak right it it's just carrying
所以说对了它只是携带
out the the strategy that it it has
出来的， 它具有 战略
computed as being the optimal solution
计算为最佳解决方案
and you know it may be that in the
而你知道它可能就是那个
process it needs to acquire more
它 需要 获得更多的过程
resources to increase the possibility of
资源 增加 的可能性
success or prevent various failure modes
成功或防止各种失败模式
by defending itself against interference
保护自己免受干扰
and so that collection of problems I
所以收集 问题我
think is something we can address yes
认为是我们可以应对 是
that the other problems are roughly
，其他问题都 大致
speaking you know misuse right so even
说你 知道滥用权利，使 连
if we solve the control problem we make
如果我们解决了我们制造的控制问题
perfectly safe controllable AI systems
完全安全可控的AI系统
well why you know why does dr. evil
以及为什么你知道为什么博士。 邪恶
going to use those right he wants to
要使用他想要的那些权利
just take over the world and he'll make
只要接管世界，他就会成功
unsafe AI system said but then get out
不安全的人工智能系统说但是后来就出去了
of control so that's one problem which
控制，这是一个问题
is sort of a you know a partly a
是排序的，你知道 一个 部分
policing problem
警务问题
partly a-- a sort of a cultural problem
部分是 - 一种文化问题
for the profession of how we teach
对于我们如何教授的职业
people what kinds of AI systems are safe
人们哪种AI系统是安全的
you talk about autonomous weapon system
你 谈论自主武器系统
and how pretty much everybody agrees
以及每个人都同意的事情
there's too many ways that that can go
有太多的方法是，可以 去
horribly wrong if this great slaughter
如果这次大屠杀， 可怕的错误
BOTS movie that kind of illustrates that
BOTS 电影那种说明
beautifully I want to talk that's
很漂亮， 我想谈谈那个
another there's another topic I I'm
另一个是我的另一个话题
happy talking about the I just want to
快乐 谈论我只是想
mention that what I see is the third
提到我看到的是第三个
major failure mode which is overuse not
过度使用的主要故障模式不是
so much misuse but overuse of AI
如此多的滥用，但过度使用AI
that we become overly dependent so I
我们变得过分依赖所以我
call this the wooly problems if you seen
如果你看到的话，把这称为 毛茸茸的问题
wall-e the movie all right all the
WALL-E电影 没事的
humans are on the spaceship and the
人类在宇宙飞船和宇宙飞船上
machines look after everything for them
机器为他们 照顾 一切
and they just watch TV and drink big
他们只是看电视 和喝酒
gulps and they're all sort of obese and
吞咽，他们都是肥胖的
stupid and they sort of totally lost any
愚蠢， 他们完全失去了任何
notion of human autonomy and
人类自治的概念
you know so a in effect right this would
你实际上这么知情权 这会
happen like the slow boiling frog right
就像慢煮的青蛙一样
we would gradually turn over more and
我们会逐渐转过来
more of the management of our
更多的是 我们 的管理
civilization to machines as we are
文明 就像我们一样机器
already doing in this you know this if
已经在这做了你知道这个
this process continues you know we sort
这个过程继续 你知道我们排序
of gradually switch from sort of being
从排序为逐渐切换
the Masters of Technology to just being
只是存在的技术大师
the guests right so so we become guests
客人这样，所以我们成为客人
on a cruise ship you know which is fine
在游轮上你知道哪个 好
for a week but not not further the rest
一个星期，但不是没有 进一步休息
of eternity right you know and it's
永恒的权利，你知道，这是
almost irreversible right once you once
一旦你有一次，几乎是不可逆转的
you lose the incentive to for example
例如，你失去了动力
you know learn to be an engineer or a
你知道学会成为一名工程师还是一名工程师
doctor or a sanitation operative or or
医生或卫生操作员或或
any other of the the infinitely many
任何其他的无限多
ways that we maintain and propagate our
我们维护 和传播我们的方式
civilization
文明
you know if you if you don't have the
如果你 没有， 你知道吗 ？
incentive to do any of that you won't
鼓励去做 你不会 做的事情
and then it's really hard to recover and
然后它真的很难 恢复 ，
of course there's just one of the
当然只有 一个
technologies that could that third
第三种技术
failure mode result in that there's
失败模式 导致有
probably other technology in general
可能是其他技术
detaches us from it does a bit but the
我们脱离它做了一点但是
the the difference is that in terms of
不同之处在于
the knowledge to to run our civilization
掌握我们文明的知识
you know up to now we've had no
你知道 到目前为止我们没有
alternative but to put it into people's
替代方案， 但把它 放入 人们的
heads right and if you oh it's not we're
朝右，如果你哦，那不是我们的
with Google I mean so software in
与谷歌我的意思是这样的软件
general so I probably if computers in
一般所以 我可能， 如果计算机在
general but but the you know the
一般但但你知道
knowledge of how you know how a
了解你如何知道如何
sanitation system works you know that's
卫生系统工作你知道的
an the AI has to understand that it's no
AI 必须明白它不是
good putting it into Google so I mean we
好把它放到谷歌所以我的意思是我们
we've always put knowledge in on paper
我们总是把知识放在纸上
but paper doesn't run our civilization
但是纸张不会影响我们的文明
it only runs when it goes from the paper
它只能从 纸张上运行
into people's heads again right so we've
再次进入人们的脑袋，这样 我们就可以了
always propagated civilization through
总是通过传播文明
human minds and we've spent about a
人类的思想，我们花了大约一个
trillion person years doing that
万亿人年这样做
literature right you you can work it out
文学对你，你可以解决
yeah but right is about just over a
是的，但 正确的是关于一个
hundred billion people who've ever lived
千百万曾经生活过的人
and each of them has spent about ten
他们 每个 人都花了大约十个人
years learning stuff and to keep their
多年学习的东西，并保持他们的
civilization going and so that's a
文明进行，所以这是一个
trillion person years we put into this
我们投入了 万亿 人年
effort beautiful way to describe all of
努力美丽的方式来描述所有 的
civilization and now we're you know
文明，现在我们你知道了
we're danger of throwing that away so
我们有把它扔掉的危险
this is a problem that AI console it's
这是一个 问题，AI控制台 是
not a technical problem it's a you know
这不是技术问题 ，你 知道
if we do our job right the AI systems
如果我们的工作正确的AI系统
will say you know the human race doesn't
会说你知道人类没有
in the long run want to be passengers in
从长远来看，希望成为乘客
a cruise ship the human race wants
邮轮上的人类希望
autonomy this is part of human
自治这是人类的一部分
preferences so we the AI systems are not
偏好所以我们AI系统不是
going to do this stuff for you you've
你会为你做这件事
got to do it for yourself right I'm not
我不得不为 自己 做这 件事
going to carry you to the top of Everest
将带你到珠穆朗玛峰的顶端
in an autonomous helicopter you have to
你需要在自主直升机上
climb it if you want to get the benefit
如果你想获得好处 ， 就去爬吧
and so on so
等等
but I'm afraid that because we are
但我害怕因为我们是
short-sighted and lazy we're gonna
短视和懒惰 我们 会
override the AI systems and and there's
覆盖AI系统，并且有
an amazing short story that I recommend
我推荐的一个惊人的短篇小说
to everyone that I talk to about this
给大家 ，我 谈谈这个
called the machine stops
叫机器停了
written in 1909 by Ian Foster who you
由 伊恩·福斯特写于1909年 谁你
know wrote novels about the British
知道写了关于英国人的小说
Empire and sort of things that became
帝国和那种 变成 的东西
costume dramas on the BBC but he wrote
英国广播公司的戏剧剧， 但他写道
this one science fiction story which is
这是一部科幻小说
an amazing vision of the future it has
它拥有令人惊叹的未来愿景
it has basically iPads it has video
它基本上有 iPad，它有 视频
conferencing it has MOOCs
会议它有MOOCs
it has computer and computer induced
它有计算机和计算机引起的
obesity I mean literally the whole thing
肥胖我的意思是整个事情
it's what people spend their time doing
这是人们 花 时间 做的事情
is giving online courses or listening to
正在提供在线课程 或听取
online courses and talking about ideas
在线 课程和 谈论的想法
but they never get out there in the real
但他们永远不会 在真实中 走出去
world that they don't really have a lot
世界他们并没有真正拥有太多
of face-to-face contact everything is
面对面接触一切都是
done online
在线完成
you know so all the things we're
你知道我们所有的事情
worrying about now were described in
担心现在被描述 为
this story and and then the human race
这个故事，然后是人类
becomes more and more dependent on the
变得越来越依赖于
Machine loses knowledge of how things
机器失去了对 事物 的了解
really run and then becomes vulnerable
真的跑了然后变得脆弱
to collapse and so it's a it's a pretty
崩溃，所以这是一个 漂亮的
unbelievably amazing story for someone
对某人来说难以置信的惊人故事
writing in 1909 to imagine all this loss
写于1909年， 想象所有这些 损失
yeah so there's very few people that
是的，所以那里的人很少
represent artificial intelligence more
代表人工智能更多
than you Russell so it's all my fault
比你拉塞尔所以这都是我的错
right you're often brought up as the
正确的你经常被提出来作为
person well Stuart Russell like the AI
人很好Stuart Russell喜欢AI
person is worried about this that's why
人很担心这 就是为什么
you should be worried about it do you
你应该担心 它
feel the burden of that I don't know if
感受到我不知道的负担
you feel that at all but when I talk to
你觉得在所有的，但是当我跟
people like from you talk about set
人们喜欢你谈论集合
people outside of computer science when
计算机科学 时 以外 的 人
they think about this still Russell is
他们认为这 仍然是罗素
worried about AI safety you should be
担心你应该 是 AI安全
worried too do you feel the burden of
担心你也感受到了负担
that I mean in a practical sense yeah
我指的是在实际意义上是的
because I'd yet you know a dozen
因为我还不知道十几个人
sometimes 25 invitations a day
有时 每天25个邀请函
to talk about it to give interviews to
谈论它给采访
write press articles and so on so in
写新闻文章等等
that very practical sense I'm seeing
我看到的那种非常实际的感觉
that people are concerned and really
人们很关心， 真的
interested about this are you worried
对此感兴趣的是你担心
that you could be wrong as all good
你可能会错，好吧
scientists are of course I worry about
科学家当然是我担心的
that all the time I mean that's that's
我一直都是这就是那个
always been the way that I I've worked
一直以来， 我 ，我的工作 方式
you know is like I have an argument in
你知道 像我 有一个说法
my head with myself right so I have some
我自己的头， 所以我有一些
idea and then I think okay how could
想法，然后我觉得好吧 怎么可能
that be wrong or did someone else
这是错的或做了其他人
already have that idea so I'll go and
已经有了这个想法，所以我会去
you know search and as much literature
你知道搜索和尽可能多的文学
as I can't to see whether someone else
因为我无法看到是否有 其他人
already thought of that or or even
已经想到了或甚至
refuted it so you know I right now I'm
反驳它，所以你现在知道我
I'm reading a lot of philosophy because
我正在阅读很多 哲学，因为
you know in in the form of the debate so
你是以辩论的形式知道的
V over utilitarianism and other kinds of
V超过功利主义和 其他类型
moral moral formulas shall we say people
道德道德公式我们应该说人
have already thought through some of
已经通过一些心思
these issues but you know what one of
这些问题，但你知道哪一位
the things I'm I'm not seeing in a lot
我 我 不是在很多看到 的东西
of these debates is this specific idea
这些辩论就是这个具体的 想法
about the importance of uncertainty in
关于不确定性的重要性
the objective that this is the way we
这就是我们的方式
should think about machines that are
应该考虑那些机器
beneficial to humans so this idea of
这样的想法 对 人类有益
provably beneficial machines based on
基于的可证明有益的机器
explicit uncertainty in the objective
目标的明确不确定性
you know it seems to be you know my gut
你知道它似乎 是你知道我的直觉
feeling is this is the core of it it's
感觉这是它的核心
gonna have to be elaborated in a lot of
必须在很多方面进行详细阐述
different directions and there are a lot
不同的方向 ，有很多
of lis beneficial yeah but they're I
这是有益的，但他们是 我
mean it has to be right we can't afford
意味着它必须 是正确的，我们负担不起
you know hand-wavy beneficial yeah
你知道手波浪有益的 耶
because there are you know whenever we
因为无论何时我们都知道
do hand wavy stuff there are loopholes
做手波浪的东西有漏洞
and the thing about super intelligent
关于超级智能的事情
machines is they find the loopholes you
机器是他们找到你的漏洞
know just like you know tax evaders if
知道，就像你知道的逃税者 如果
you don't write your tax law properly
你没有正确地写你的税法
that people will find loopholes and end
人们会发现漏洞并结束
up paying no taxes and
不付税和
and so you should think of it this way
所以你应该这样想
and in getting those definitions right
并使这些定义正确
you know it is really a long process you
你知道这确实是一个漫长的过程，你
know so you can you can define
知道所以你可以定义
mathematical frameworks and within that
数学框架及其内部
framework you can prove mathematical
框架你可以证明数学
theorems that yes this will you know
定理是的，你知道吗？
this this theoretical entity will be
这个理论实体将是
proven beneficial to that theoretical
证明对理论有益
entity but that framework may not match
实体，但该框架可能不匹配
the real world in some crucial way so
现实世界在某种关键方面如此
long process thinking through it of
通过它思考的漫长过程
iterating and so on the last question
迭代等等最后一个问题
yep you have ten seconds to answer it
是的， 你有 十秒钟 回答 它
what is your favorite sci-fi movie about
什么是你最喜欢的科幻电影
AI I would say interstellar has my
AI 我会说 星际有我的
favorite robots or beat it Space Odyssey
最喜欢的机器人或击败太空奥德赛
yeah yeah yeah so so tars the robots one
是的是的是的，所以对机器人这么说
of the robots in interstellar is the way
星际机器人的方式
a robot should behave
一个机器人应该表现
and I would say ex machina is in some
我会说ex machina在某些
ways the one like the one that makes you
那个人就像那个让你成功的人
think in a nervous kind of way about a
认为在大约一个紧张的一种方式
lot where we're going well Stuart thank
我们很顺利的地方 斯图尔特谢谢
you so much for talking today pleasure
你今天非常高兴地谈论快乐
you
您